片名《换子疑云》
一个真实的故事
洛杉矶 1928年3月9日
沃特,宝贝
Walter, honey.
该起床了
Time to wake up.
再让我睡10分钟
Just 10 more minutes.
那可不行，小运动家 你可以明天再睡个够
Oh, I'm sorry, sport. You can sleep in tomorrow.
星期六才是用来睡懒觉的
That's what Saturdays are for.
靠墙站好
Up against the wall.
来，来，来
Come, come, come.
好了
All right.
好了，你看看！
Got it. Got it. Look, look!
好了，坐下吧
All right, sit down.
你的早餐要冷掉了
Your breakfast is getting cold.
明明就是麦片
It's cereal.
麦片本来就是冷的
It's supposed to be cold.
甜心，我们到了
Sweetheart, we're here.
走吧
Okay.
这是你的书
Here's your books.
去吧
Go ahead.
好的，女士，请您稍微等一下 我去给你找下主管
Yes, ma'am. If you hold just a moment, I'll get a supervisor for you.
好的，她马上就过来
Yes, she's coming right now.
稍等一下，她马上就到
Just a second, she'll be with you.
请您稍等 你来处理这事，我管不了了
Just one second, please. You deal with this one. I'm not going near it.
你好，我是主管 我能帮你做什么？
Hello, this is the supervisor. How can I help you?
我发现你那里有多个用户在通话
I can see you're on a party line...
很遗憾，的确会有人通过多人电话偷听，我们…
Unfortunately, some people do listen in on party lines. We...
他在干什么？
Well, what is he doing?
哦，我的…
Oh, my...
一切都还好吧？
Everything all right?
是的，长官，一切正常 有位女士暂时无法接通
Yes, sir, it's fine. A lady was having trouble with the connection.
嘿，小运动家 嘿，妈妈
Hey, sport. Hey, Mom.
你在学校怎么样？
How was school?
还行 是吗？
Okay. Yeah?
我们教了恐龙
We learned about dinosaurs.
然后我和比利・曼克维斯基打了架
And I got in a fight with Billy Mankowski.
怎么回事？
What happened?
他打我
He hit me.
你打回去了？
Did you hit him back?
干的好
Good.
第一条，还记得吗？
Rule number one, remember?
永远不要主动打架，但要做个赢家
Never start a fight, always finish it.
他为什么要打你呢？
Why'd he hit you?
因为我打了他
Because I hit him.
你先打他的？
You hit him first?
为什么打他？
Why?
他说爸爸是因为不喜欢我才走的
He said my dad ran off because he didn't like me.
宝贝，你爸爸根本没有见过你
Honey, your father never met you,
那他又怎么会不喜欢你呢？
so how could he not like you?
可他为什么要走呢？
Then why did he leave?
因为在你出生的那天
Well, because the day you were born,
他收到了一个包裹
something else arrived in the mail.
是个比你稍微大一点的盒子
And it was in a box a little bit bigger than you.
你知道里面装的是什么吗？
You know what was in it?
是一种叫做责任的东西
Something called responsibility.
对有些人来说
And to some people,
责任是世界上最最吓人的事情
responsibility is the scariest thing in the world.
所以，他离开是因为盒子里有个最最吓人的东西？
So, he ran away because he was scared of what was in that box?
嗯-哼
Uh-huh.
听起来好傻
That's just dumb.
我也是这么想的
That is exactly what I thought.
我是不是错过《阿莫斯和安迪》了？ [备注：20年代在美国很流行的情景喜剧]
Did I miss Amos 'N Andy?
恐怕是的，小运动家
I'm afraid so, sport.
来吧，该睡觉了
Come now, time for bed.
我们明天还去看电影吗？
Are we still going to the movies tomorrow?
嗯哼，我听说有一部查理・卓别林的新电影
Uh-huh. I hear there's a new Charlie Chaplin picture
还有一部新的连续剧，叫做神秘的飞行员
and a new serial called The Mysterious Airman.
那是谁？
Who's that?
不知道，没有人知道
I don't know. Nobody does.
所以他才会那么神秘
That's what makes him so mysterious.
哦
Oh.
是不是我太重，你抱不动了？
Am I too heavy for you to carry?
哦，不是，至少这几年还不会
Oh, no, not for years.
这几年
Not for years.
- 你好？ - 我是玛格瑞特
Hello? This is Margaret.
嗨，玛格瑞特
Hi, Margaret.
你过的还好吧？
So, how are you?
挺好的
Fine.
我想跟你说，简今天没法来了，我们这里缺个人
Listen, Jean can't come in today and now we're a little shorthanded.
她什么时候打电话来说生病的？
When did she call in sick?
大概半个小时前
About half hour ago.
这时候我实在找不到其他人
I'm having a hard time trying to find someone.
摩尔娜呢？
Well, what about Myrna?
我知道她肯定愿意花个把钟头，而且…
I know she could use the extra hours and...
她很忙的，你不能来帮忙吗？
She's busy. Can't you come?
不行 不，我不是这个意思，只是…
No. No, no, no. I just...
我答应沃特说要带他去看电影的，所以…
I promised Walter that I'd take him to the movies, is all, and...
没事的，就到4点
Well, it's just until 4:00.
那好吧
All right.
但是… 就到4点
Just... Just until 4:00.
我们等下见
I'll see you then.
冰箱里有三明治和牛奶
There's a sandwich and milk in the fridge,
我已经请莱利太太和她女儿
and I've asked Mrs. Riley and her daughter
过来照顾你几个小时了
to stop in in a couple of hours.
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
我知道你可以的，他们是来照看房子，不是照顾你的
I know you can. They're checking on the house, not you.
明天我们就去看电影
Tomorrow we will go to the movies.
然后我们会坐大红号去圣莫尼卡 在那边的码头散步
And then we'll ride Big Red to Santa Monica and take a walk on the pier.
你觉得怎么样？听起来会很好玩吧？
How does that sound? Does that sound good?
天黑之前我会回家的
I'll be home before it gets dark.
我不怕黑
I'm not afraid of the dark.
我什么都不怕
I'm not afraid of anything.
我知道，我知道
I know. I know.
乖乖的
Be good.
我爱你
I love you.
我们这里到俄亥俄州的线路堵住了
We've got lines jammed from here to Ohio.
他说他要跟负责人讲话
He says he needs to speak to somebody in charge.
我要申请些日用必需品，帮我签个名
I need your signature here for a supply requisition.
请问您要接什么号码？ 您要接什么号码？
Number, please. Number, please.
请继续
Go ahead, please.
好了，给我接奥马哈中继站
All right, get me the Omaha routing station.
看看我们能不能通过那里中转电话
See if we can put our calls through their switchers.
让我们试试看吧
Let's get this console running, now.
克莉斯汀，做得不错 我一直想要找你
Christine. Good, I was hoping to catch you.
听着，我一直在关注你的工作情况
Look, I've been following your work reports,
我想告诉你的是我非常满意
and I just want to let you know that I am very impressed.
最初我建议使用女性接线员当主管的时候
When I first suggested hiring female supervisors,
上头表现地不是很感冒
my superiors weren't big on the idea.
结果你的表现和你的那些男同事一样出色
But you have held your own as well as any of your male counterparts.
谢谢夸奖，哈里斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Harris.
哦，本，请你不要 听着，我…
Oh, Ben, please. Listen, I...
听着，重点是
Listen, the point is,
我们准备给我们新的贝佛利山办公室找个经理
we're looking to take on a manager for our new Beverly Hills office.
如果你有兴趣的话，我可以给你打个报告，或者…
And if you're interested in the job, I could write a report, or...
那再好不过了，太谢谢你了，先生
That would be wonderful. Thank you so much, sir.
没错，很好 那么，也许我们可以…
Okay, good, so maybe we could...
我们可以好好谈一下 星期一，当然可以，没问题
Could we speak about it Monday? Yeah, absolutely.
星期一真的可以吗？非常感谢，谢谢您，先生
Would that be all right? Thank you so much, sir. Thank you.
等一下！
Please!
别走
Please.
沃特
Walter.
宝贝？
Honey?
沃特
Walter.
沃特!
Walter!
宝贝？
Honey?
沃特?
Walter?
宝贝！
Honey!
沃特!
Walter!
沃特，回家的时间到了，宝贝
Walter, it's time to come in, honey.
苏希，你看见沃特没有？
Suzie? Have you seen Walter?
没有，柯林斯太太
No, Mrs. Collins.
抱歉
Sorry.
沃特?
Walter?
沃特
Walter.
请告诉我您要拨打的号码
Number, please.
请给我接警察局
May I please have the police station?
我正在帮您接通
I'll connect you.
这里是林肯高地分局
Lincoln Heights Division.
你好，我叫克莉斯汀・柯林斯
Hello, my name is Christine Collins.
我住在北大街210号23楼
I live at 210 North Avenue, 23.
我要报失踪
And I'm calling to report a missing child.
失踪儿童
Missing child.
女士，你和孩子的关系是？
What's your relation to the child, ma'am?
是我的儿子
It's my son.
他不见多长时间了？
How long has he been gone?
我也不知道，我刚下班回家
I'm not sure. I just got home from work.
可能是今天早上
It could be since this morning
也有可能就在刚才
or it could be just the last hour.
你在附近找过了吗？
Have you checked around the neighborhood?
是的，我当然找过了
Yes, of course I did.
那，也有可能他玩的忘了时间了
Well, maybe he's lost track of time.
不，不，不会的
No. No, no.
天黑了以后他肯定会呆在房子里的
He always stays around the house when it gets dark.
你能不能派人来这里？
Would you please send someone down here?
很抱歉，根据我们的制度
I'm sorry, but our policy is that
只有在孩子失踪超过24小时后我们才会派人进行搜救
we don't dispatch units on missing child cases for 24 hours.
什么？
What?
你知道吗，这种案子十有八九小孩子会在第二天早上回来的
Look, 99 times out of 100, the kid shows up by morning.
我们可没有那么多人手来找每个 和朋友跑出去玩的小家伙
We don't have the resources to go chasing every kid who runs off with his pals.
不，不，不是那样的
No, no, no.
沃特不是那样的，他从来不会那么做
No, that's not Walter. He doesn't do that.
请原谅我实话实说，太太 每个家长都是这么跟我说的
With all due respect, ma'am, every parent who calls says the same thing.
求你了，求你了
Please, please.
你看，我没有办法帮你
Look, there's nothing I can do.
我会记下你的名字和其他信息
I'll take your name and your information,
不过最快要到明天早上我们才能派人
but that's all until the morning, at the earliest.
我确定他会在那之前回来的，孩子们都这样
I'm sure he'll show up by then. They always do.
你是柯林斯太太？
Are you Mrs. Collins?
我们今天将为来自林肯高地的
Our thoughts go out again today to Mrs. Christine Collins
克莉斯汀・柯林斯太太祈祷
of Lincoln Heights,
她的孩子沃特・柯林斯
whose young son, Walter Collins,
在大概两周前失踪了
disappeared nearly two weeks ago.
尽管她并非我们的成员
Though she is not a member of our congregation,
我们会和往常一样为她祈祷
we pray for her today as we have every day,
因为我们知道她的困境
since we learned of her plight.
从报纸和广播里
On the radio and in the newspapers
我们知道洛杉矶警局
we are told that the Los Angeles Police Department
正在尽力帮助这位母亲和她的儿子团聚
is doing its very best to reunite mother and child,
我相信他们没有撒谎
and I'm sure that that is true.
但是作为洛基山脉西边
But given its status as the most violent, corrupt
最暴力、腐败和最不称职
and incompetent police department
的警察分局
this side of the Rocky Mountains
我不清楚他们是否对此有足够的重视
I am not sure it's saying a great deal.
每一天，穆赫兰道或是城市的路沟边
Every day, new bodies appear along Mulholland
都有新的尸体出现
and in the ditches of our cities,
对于警察局长詹姆斯・戴维斯 和他手下的炮团来说
the work of Police Chief James Davis and his aptly named Gun Squad.
众多市民的真正需求被弃置一旁
Every day, the needs of honest citizens
取而代之的是贪婪和中饱私囊
are put second to greed and personal gain.
这个城市正在一天天的沉沦
Every day, this city sinks deeper into a cesspool
变成充斥惊惧、恐吓和腐败的污水池
of fear, intimidation and corruption.
在洛杉矶，曾经的天使之城里
Once the City of Angels,
我们的保护者
Los Angeles has become a place where our protectors
转而成为了施暴者
have become our brutalizers.
法律的守护者却悍然践踏法律之上
Where to be the law is to be above the law.
1928年4月3日
我知道了，谢谢你
I understand. Thank you.
我过几个星期会再给你电话的
I will call back in a few weeks.
非常谢谢你
Thank you very much.
拉斯维加斯失踪人口科？
Las Vegas Missing Persons Department?
你好，我是克莉斯汀・柯林斯
Hello, this is Christine Collins.
我想问下你那里有没有找到
I'm calling to see if you've found any missing or lost children
符合沃特・柯林斯外貌特征的失踪儿童
who meet the description that matches Walter Collins.
哦，我知道了，好的，如果有消息的话，请你务必给我电话
Oh, all right. Well, please do. Please do call.
如果可以，我会再打电话给…
And I'll call back in a matter...
再过一周打过来，非常感谢你
In a week, if that's all right. Thank you very much.
谢谢你
Thank you.
2美金
$2.
该死的，我大概是把钱包落在家里了
Hell, I think I left my wallet at home.
我能先欠着么？
Can I owe it to you?
不行
No credit.
付钱，不然我就叫警察了
Pay up or I call the cops.
你这种无赖让我恶心
I'm sick of bums like you coming around here.
我也不想让你难做，厨子
I'm not trying to stiff you, chief.
我只是把钱包落在家里了
I just left my wallet at home, that's all.
我现在就回去拿，5分钟，不，最多就10分钟
I'll go back and get it. Five, 10 minutes, tops.
你有东西抵押么？
Got collateral?
那么没什么比把我的亲生骨肉
You can't ask for better collateral
抵押在这里更让你放心的了吧
than a man's own flesh and blood, right?
孩子，现在你等在这里
Now, you stay here, son.
我很快就回来
I'll be right back.
不过…你别给我惹麻烦
But... Now, don't give me any trouble.
这位先生肯信我们，他是个好人
He's a good man to trust us like this.
你现在给我乖乖等在这里，我回去拿我的钱包
Now, you just stay here and I'll go back and get my wallet.
给你10分钟，不然我就打电话给警察
Ten minutes, then I call the cops.
啊，该死
Ah, hell.
请您告诉我要接通的号码 哈，莫尔托?
Number, please. Hello, Myrtle?
哈，你好，我是哈尔夫，饭店的那个
Hello? Yeah, this is Harve, down at the diner.
哦，嗨，哈尔夫
Oh, hi, Harve.
能帮我找下治安官拉尔森吗？
Would you get me Sheriff Larsen?
没问题
Sure thing.
你今天过得很不错吧
You have a nice day, too.
克莉斯汀，我这里接不通
Christine, I'm having trouble with the connection here.
我怎么也没法接通
I can't seem to get through.
我想是这样，嗯，我想这样会好些
I think so. Yeah, I think that's better.
你有个私人电话 费尔法克斯2331
You have a person to person call, Fairfax 2231.
是个长途电话，对不起，请您再说一遍？
Long distance. Sorry, can you repeat?
马上给您接过去，女士
I'll connect you right away, ma'am.
谢谢
Thanks.
柯林斯太太？
Mrs. Collins?
我是
Yes.
我是J.J.琼斯上尉 林肯公园少年案件组的
I'm Captain J.J. Jones, Lincoln Park Juvenile Division.
我这里负责处理所有离家出走和失踪儿童的案件
My office supervises all runaway and missing child cases,
包括你儿子的案子 然后…
including your son's, and...
他还活着，柯林斯太太
He's alive, Mrs. Collins.
两天前他被伊利诺斯州德卡博当地的警察发现了
He was picked up two days ago by local police in DeKalb, Illinois.
他很安全，没有受伤
He's safe and unhurt.
他跟一群流浪汉混迹在一起， 我们在查全境通告时发现了他 [APB：all-points bulletin 全美法务机构联网发布通告的系统]
He was in the company of some drifter. We have an APB out for him,
不过他现在很安全
but he's safe.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
哦，克莉斯汀...
Oh, Christine...
这实在是太好了
That is so great.
谢谢你
Thank you.
外面有好多记者
There's so much press.
因为你的故事有个好的结局 柯林斯太太
Yours is a story with a happy ending, Mrs. Collins.
大家都喜欢看到圆满结局
People love happy endings.
我们最好走快点，火车已经进站了
We better get a move on, the train's pulling in.
后退，伙计们，后退
Back, boys. Back.
谢谢，谢谢，小伙子们，谢谢
Thanks. Thanks, boys, thanks!
等会儿我会演说的
I'll have a statement for you in a few minutes,
不过现在最重要的事情
but the important thing right now
是让这位夫人和她的儿子团聚
is to reunite this little lady with her son,
所以请你们给我们留些时间
so if you'll excuse us.
慢点，不要跑
Stay right there. Come on, don't rush.
慢点，慢点
Easy, easy.
柯林斯太太，请允许我向你介绍詹姆斯・戴维斯
Mrs. Collins, I'd like to introduce you to James E. Davis,
警察局长
Chief of Police.
很高兴见到你
Very nice to meet you.
最近这段时间里，我们可从来没
We don't get a lot of positive attention
从媒体那些家伙那儿获得过正面评价
from the boys in the press these days,
所以能有个圆满的结局对我们彼此来说 都是再好不过了，你说是吧？
so it's good to be here with a positive story, don't you think?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
我手底下的人对你的态度还好吧？
I take it you've been treated well by my boys in the department?
他们说我必须等人失踪24小时之后才报案
I couldn't file a report for 24 hours,
我觉得也许是不是可以…
and I thought that maybe that was a...
不算制度上的问题呢
Technicalities aside.
很好了
It was wonderful.
好的，很好
Well, good.
那么你应该可以毫不犹豫地告诉那些记者
Then you won't have any trouble telling that to the press,
实际上洛杉矶警局…
and the fact that the LAPD...
女人
Women.
等一下，长官
Hold on a second.
伙计们，后退，后退
Back, boys, back.
让他们往后退
Keep them back.
好了，你是不是可以…请你…
Well, aren't you... Aren't you gonna...
这不是我的儿子
That's not my son.
什么？
What?
你刚刚说什么？
What are you saying?
这不是我的儿子
It's not my son.
是吗，我觉得你肯定是搞错了
Well, I'm sure you're mistaken.
我没有弄错
I'm not mistaken.
你看，他这5个月来吃不好睡不好
Well, he's been through five terrible long months.
所以他瘦了，样子也变了
He's lost weight, he's changed.
我难道不认识我自己的儿子吗？
I would know my own son.
我只能说你是太激动看错了 而且他样子也变了
All I'm saying is you're in shock and he's changed.
你叫什么名字？能告诉我你的名字吗？
What's your name? Can you tell me your name?
沃特・柯林斯.
Walter Collins.
这名字很多人用
It's a common name.
你住在哪里？沃特? 你知道家里的地址吗？
Where do you live, Walter? You know your home address?
我住在加利福尼亚，洛杉矶
I live at 210 Avenue 23,
西大街210号，23楼
Los Angeles, California.
她就是我妈妈！
And that's my mommy!
柯林斯太太, 听我说，我明白你的心情
Mrs. Collins, listen to me. I understand.
你现在是不是觉得很忐忑，不敢确定？ 这是很常见的
You're feeling a little uncertain right now, and that's to be expected.
这样年纪的孩子变得非常快
A boy this age, he changes so fast.
我们在检查的时候就确认过了
We've compensated for that in our investigation.
毫无疑问，他就是你的孩子
And there's no question that this is your son.
他不是沃特
That is not Walter.
他不是你记忆里的沃特
It's not Walter as you remember him.
所以说你带他回去以后 进行一段时间的试生活是很有必要的
And that's why it's important for you to take him home on a trial basis.
试生活？
A trial basis?
是的，是的
Yes, yes.
等他回到自己熟悉的环境后
Once he's around his familiar surroundings,
你要给他点时间 好从惊吓里恢复过来
and you've given yourself time to recover from the shock of his changed condition,
你就知道，他肯定是你的沃特
you will see that this is your Walter.
现在，我可以给你保证，我的话肯定没错
Now, I promise you, I swear to you, I give you my word.
他是你的儿子
This is your son.
现在，如果你还有任何问题，任何的问题都可以 请你告诉我
Now, if you have any problems, any problems at all, you come and you talk to me.
我来帮你处理
I'll take care of it.
我向你保证，相信我
I give you my word. Trust me.
柯林斯太太, 他没有别的地方可以去
Mrs. Collins, he has nowhere else to go.
求你了
Please.
也许是我糊涂了
Maybe I'm not thinking clearly.
而且…
And...
好吧
All right.
没错，是你刚才糊涂了，这样才对
All right, you're not thinking clearly, that's right.
我们走吧！
Here we go!
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
这里，在这里转弯
Here, just turn around here.
终于把你的孩子找回家了，说说你的感想吧 柯林斯太太？
How does it feel to have your son home, Mrs. Collins?
当你再一次见到你儿子的时候，想到了什么？
What'd you think when you saw him for the first time?
很难用语言描述
It's hard to explain.
一开始她有些惊讶
She was shocked at first.
她没有认出自己的孩子，不过这也很正常
She didn't recognize the boy, which is perfectly natural.
小家伙也遭受了不少磨难
He's been through quite an ordeal.
孩子，你现在在想什么？
How're you feeling, son?
能回到家心里一定很高兴吧
Bet it feels great to be home.
是的，非常高兴
Yeah. It's great.
洛杉矶警察局非常感谢
The Los Angeles Police Department is thankful
德卡博郡治安官的不懈努力
for all the hard work done by the DeKalb County Sheriff's Department
让我们见到了这一场温馨的重逢
in making this joyful reunion possible.
洛杉矶警局时刻服务大众
The LAPD is dedicated to serving the public at all times.
长官，我们能给孩子和他母亲照张合影吗？
Can we get a photo with mother and son, Captain?
当然可以！就这里拍吧
Absolutely! Here we are.
这样，就这样
Like that. Like that.
靠紧点，拍吧，朋友们
Squeeze together. There you go, boys.
沃特，朝这里看，笑得开心点
This way, Walter. Big smile.
再来一张吧，嗯，这个表情不错
One more, please. That's a good one.
再来一张
One more.
三明治还好吃吗？
The sandwich all right?
你要喝点牛奶吗？
Would you like some more milk?
不用了
No.
说不用了，谢谢
No, thank you.
不用了，谢谢
火车弄得你满脸都是灰，你应该去洗个澡
You're covered in soot from the train. You should take a bath.
睡衣我给你放在床边了
Pajamas are on the edge of the bed.
你还好吧？没事吧？
You okay? You all right?
我觉得像个傻瓜！
I fell. Stupid tub!
没事的
That's all right.
你切过包皮了
You're circumcised.
出来
Get out.
快点
Move.
上次我给沃特
Last time I measured Walter,
上一次我给我儿子量身高的时候
last time I measured my son,
他比你现在要高多了
he was inches taller than you are now.
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
你到底在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
你是谁？
Who are you?
他不是我儿子
He's not my son.
柯林斯太太...
Mrs. Collins...
我不知道，我不知道为什么他要说自己是
No, I don't know why he's saying that he is,
但他不是沃特，我不会搞错的
but he's not Walter and there's been a mistake.
我记得我们上次说好，给他适应的时间
I thought we agreed to give him time to adjust.
他比我儿子矮了3英寸
He's three inches shorter.
我和以前的记号比过了
I measured him on the chart.
可能是你量歪了呢
Well, maybe your measurements are off.
你看，关于这事情我们肯定能找到个合适的解释
Look, I'm sure there's a reasonable explanation for all of this.
他割过包皮了
He's circumcised.
沃特没有
And Walter isn't.
柯林斯太太
Mrs. Collins.
你的儿子失踪了5个月
Your son was missing for five months.
这5个月里，他有很长时间 是和一群没有身份的流浪汉呆在一起
For at least part of that time in the company of an as yet unidentified drifter.
谁知道这些经常扰乱治安的家伙们会做些什么
Who knows what such a disturbed individual might have done?
他可能给孩子割了包皮，也可能…
He could have had him circumcised. He could have...
让他变矮么？
Made him shorter?
你为什么不肯听我呢？
Why aren't you listening to me?
我在听啊，该死的，我听你说了
I am listening, damn it, I am listening.
我明白你现在的感受
And I understand your feelings.
他样子有些变了，但不会错，还有…
He's changed, no mistake, and that's...
你们都度过了一段糟糕的日子
You've both been through a terrible experience,
他需要你的爱和支持，然后慢慢恢复过来
and that's why he needs your love and support to bounce back.
他不是我儿子！
He's not my son!
你为什么还要坚持这么说，柯林斯太太？
Why are you doing this, Mrs. Collins?
你干吗这样呢？
Why are you doing this?
你完全有能力照顾这个孩子
You seem perfectly capable of taking care of the boy.
你的工资足够负担他的一切生活需求
Your job pays you enough to attend to his personal needs,
所以我不明白你为什么要逃避
so I don't understand why you're running away
你作为母亲的责任
from your responsibilities as a mother.
我没有要逃避任何东西！
I am not running away from anything!
不要谈什么责任了
Least of all my responsibilities!
我现在还在照顾这个孩子！
I am even taking care of that boy right now,
因为他无处可去！
because I am all he has!
我担心的是你们因此就不去找我的儿子了！
What worries me is that you have stopped looking for my son!
我们干吗要去找一个已经被找回来的人？
Why should we be looking for someone we've already found?
因为你们还没找到他
Because you have not found him.
我们已经确认他的身份了
His identity has been confirmed
我们这里有儿童鉴定的权威
by the best minds in the field of child identification,
他们知道自己在做什么
people who know what they're doing.
你是说我不知道？
And I don't?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我十分感谢警察局所作的一切
I appreciate everything that this department has done
我也知道你们花了很多力气
and I know how hard you're working.
我真的很感谢你们，而且我也不想给你们添麻烦
I really do, and I don't want to cause any trouble.
但是…这是个很大的误会
I just... There has been a terrible mistake,
我希望你们能帮助我解决这个误会
and I need you to help me correct it,
好让我能在儿子出什么意外前找到他
so I can find my son before it's too late.
求你了
Please.
我不想再浪费你的时间了 我很失望
I won't take up any more of your time. I'm sorry I got upset.
对不起，很对不起
I'm sorry, very sorry.
长官，什么事？
Yes, Captain?
萨拉，你去找下塔尔医生
Sara, get Dr. Tarr on the phone.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
柯林斯太太？ 是我
Mrs. Collins? Yes?
我是伊尔・塔尔医生
Dr. Earl W. Tarr.
是琼斯上尉派我来的
Captain Jones sent me.
我一直帮助他做青少年案件的咨询
I consult with him from time to time on juvenile cases.
我能进来吗？
May I come in?
请进，谢谢你能过来
Yes, thank you for coming.
我还以为他根本不相信我说的话
I was beginning to think he didn't believe me.
你看，我不是来了吗 我们会解决一切问题的
Well, I'm here now, and we'll put all that to rights.
那个孩子在哪里？
Where's the boy?
啊！在这里
Ah! There he is.
英俊的小家伙
A handsome young man.
他的眼睛很像你，不是吗？
He has your eyes, doesn't he?
鼻子也挺像的
And a little bit of the nose.
很健壮，生他的时候很辛苦吧
Very fit, in spite of all his travails.
你有个很健康的孩子啊，柯林斯太太
A very resilient boy you've got here, Mrs. Collins.
我以为你是过来帮我找孩子的
I thought you were here to help me.
当然
Well, I am.
琼斯上尉说这个孩子的体格变了不少
Captain Jones said that the boy had been through some severe physical changes
所以要我来看看他
and asked me to drop in on him
确保你尽到了做母亲的责任
to reassure you in your time of motherly concern.
他不是我的儿子，我没有照顾他的义务
My motherly concern is not for him because he's not my son.
你现在的话很容易伤害到孩子的自尊
Now, statements like that will hardly help the boy's self-esteem,
对吗？
now will they?
琼斯上尉提到了身高的事情
Captain Jones said something about a change in height?
是的
Yes.
过来
Come.
靠墙站好
Against the wall.
他足足比我儿子矮了3英寸
He's three inches shorter.
啊，好吧…
Ah, well...
这的确是个谜题，柯林斯太太
Hardly a mystery, Mrs. Collins.
我们都知道，有时候精神创伤会影响孩子的成长
We've known for some time that trauma can affect the growth of children.
过去5个月里他经受的紧张压力
Given the stress of the past five months,
可能让他的脊椎出现了收缩
his spine may have actually shrunk.
非常罕见，但并非毫无可能
It's uncommon, but it's within the realm of possibility.
那割包皮的事呢？
And circumcision?
很有可能是诱拐他的人做的
Very likely his abductor thought it appropriate.
从生理卫生的角度来看，割掉包皮值得提倡
After all, circumcision is hygienically sound.
当时给他造成的刺激一定很大
Must have been quite traumatic at the time.
所以他选择忘掉那段记忆
No wonder he's submerged the memory.
我…
I...
你看，你所提出的疑点都有完美的医学解释
You see, there's a perfectly sound medical explanation for all of this.
当然了，你有权力提出质疑
But it's right for you to raise the questions.
你必须理解，在他失踪的那段时间里
You need to be apprised of all changes the lad went through
这个孩子可能出现各种变化
during his absence.
我难道还会不知道他是不是我儿子吗？
Wouldn't I know whether or not he's my son?
我是母亲
I'm the mother.
也意味着你没法客观冷静地来看待这个问题
Which means you're in no position to be objective.
你太钻牛角尖了，只关注孩子的过去
You are looking through the prism of extreme emotion at a boy
而这个孩子跟你记忆中的形象出入很大
who has changed from what you remember.
他和离开这里时的孩子不一样了
He isn't the same boy that left here.
就好像参军回来的孩子
Just as a boy that goes off to war and then returns
和以前大不相同
is not the same anymore.
而母亲的判断往往依靠的是直觉和情绪
And a mother's heart, driven by intuition and emotion,
在发现这些改变后起了抵触心理
sees these changes and rebels,
所以才坚持说这不是你的孩子
insists that this isn't your son.
但事实是无法改变的
Doesn't change the facts.
请让我用更客观的方法来证明我的理论 柯林斯太太
I'm willing to put my theory to the test of objectivity, Mrs. Collins.
你来吗？
Are you?
这实在是太过分了！
It is absolutely outrageous!
你先冷静下来，冷静，好好听我说
Calm yourself, calm yourself and just listen to me.
不，不是，请你听我说
No, no, no. No, you listen to me, please.
这个所谓的医生把我带到我的邻居面前转悠
This so called doctor paraded me around my own neighborhood,
说得好像我是个失职到连自己的儿子都认不出来的妈妈
like some kind of a derelict mother who didn't even know her own son.
他的结论是什么？
And what was his findings?
他只得到了他想要的结论
He found what he expected to find,
很明显也就是你希望他得出的结论
what you obviously told him he would find.
柯林斯太太，这不是…
Mrs. Collins. But that's not...
没有什么好懊恼伤心的
That's nothing to be embarrassed about.
我伤不伤心不是重点
That I was embarrassed is not the issue.
重点是你在浪费时间
The point is that you are wasting time
你真正应该做的是去找我的儿子
when you should be looking for my son.
很遗憾，交完报告就都结束了 柯林斯太太
But the report is final, Mrs. Collins.
是吗，那我希望能收到报告 在这份报告交给任何人之前
Well, then I want to receive the report, so I can refute it,
我要拒绝接受这份报告
before it goes to anyone else.
随便你
Fine.
谢谢，再见
Yes. Good day.
没有我的事了，我能不能回自己房间？
I'm finished. Could I go to my room now?
去吧
Yes.
晚安，妈妈
Good night, Mommy.
不准你再这样叫！
Stop saying that!
不准你叫！
我不是你的妈妈！
I'm not your mother!
我只要把我的儿子找回来
I want my son back.
你不是他，你不是我的儿子！
You're not him. You're not my son!
我要我的儿子回来
I want my son back.
我要我的儿子回来！
I want my son back!
你真该死！
Damn you!
我要我的儿子回来!
I want my son back!
我不应该对你大吼大叫的
I was wrong to yell at you.
你只是个孩子
You're just a child
我想你也不知道自己正在做什么
and I don't think you know what you're doing,
还有你的到来给我带来的伤害
and the hurt you're causing.
但是你必须知道一件事，我的儿子就是我的生命
But I need you to understand that my son is my life.
他就是我的一切
He's all I have.
不管警察是怎么想的，我也不管世界上所有人怎么想
And no matter what the police think, and no matter what the world thinks,
你和我
you and I,
我们都知道这是错的，对吗？
we both know the truth, don't we?
我们都清楚你不是沃特
We both know that you're not Walter.
你只要告诉他们说你不是我的儿子
You just have to tell them that you're not my son,
然后他们就会找到我儿子了
so they can find my son.
求求你
Please.
我们明天再说吧
We can talk tomorrow.
哈？
Hello?
是克莉斯汀・柯林斯太太吗？
Is this Mrs. Christine Collins?
我是
Yes.
我的名字叫做古斯塔夫・布里格勒博
My name is Gustav Briegleb.
我是圣保罗教会的牧师
I'm the pastor over at St. Paul's Presbyterian.
哦，我知道你，我听过你的广播
Oh, yes, I've heard your broadcasts.
我…
I'm...
谢谢你
Thank you.
你读过今天的泰晤士报了没？
Have you read the Times this morning?
没有
No.
也许你应该先去读一下 然后过来教堂这里吃早餐
Well, maybe you should give it a gander and then come over here to the parish
大约一个小时之后，我们会再见的
for breakfast, in, say, an hour. I think we should meet.
哈？
Hello?
神秘案件…
"Mysterious case of...
应洛杉矶警局的要求
"Acting on the request of the Los Angeles Police Department,
儿童专家伊尔・塔尔医生为沃特・柯林斯
"Dr. Earl W. Tarr, child specialist, examined Walter Collins
作了检查，以了解造成他变矮的原因
"to determine the cause of his loss of weight,
自从星期一这个孩子
"paleness, confusion, and rundown condition
回到他母亲的身边之后
"noticed since the return of the boy
显得苍白、疑惑、摇摇欲坠
"To his mother last Monday. "
用词很优美，不是吗？
Lovely bit of phrasing, isn't it?
他提到自从孩子回到他母亲身边后
Noticed since the return of the boy to his mother.
现在不只是证明了你就是这男孩的妈妈
Now, not only does that clearly state you're the boy's mother,
还指出说你应该为这些改变负责
but one could infer from it that you're somehow responsible for these changes.
而且警察局开始关注
And that the police department is concerned
在你的监护下孩子的生活状况
for the boy's welfare while he's in your charge.
尝尝煎蛋，做的非常好
You should try the eggs. They're very nice.
我给那男孩做了全面检查，塔尔医生说
"'I examined the boy quite thoroughly,' Dr. Tarr said,
很明显这孩子有些话要跟我说
"'And it's clear that he has something to tell.
我很确定不久之后…
"'I'm sure that in time... "'
他会把整件事情的来龙去脉告诉我们
...time he will give his boyish story of the entire affair,
不过那要等到他有信心讲给他的听众
but not until he has faith in his listener.
而那正是他缺少的， 一位听众和让这个可怜孩子讲出经历的信心
And that is what is lacking here, faith in the poor lad's story.
经过检查，我的结论和洛杉矶警局
Course of my examination, I found nothing to dispute the findings
得出的结论是一致的
of the LAPD.
他们为什么这么做？
Why would they do this?
这样才能避免承认他们犯了错误
To avoid admitting they made a mistake
承认说他们找错了孩子
when they brought back the wrong boy.
只要是稍微有点脑子的人在读了报纸以后
Of course, anyone reading the newspaper with half a brain
肯定会对此表示怀疑
would see through it instantly.
很遗憾的是 同时也意味着直接将泰晤士报的一半读者给抹掉了
Sadly, that would exclude about half the readership of the Times.
柯林斯太太，我一直致力于找出隐藏在各类事情后的真相
Mrs. Collins, I have made it my mission in life to bring to light all the things
洛杉矶警局不希望让人发现他们的错误
the LAPD wish none of us ever knew about.
这是一个充斥着暴力、滥用职权 谋杀、腐败和恐吓的警察局
A department ruled by violence, abuse, murder, corruption and intimidation.
两年前戴维斯局长接手的时候他说
When Chief Davis took over the force two years ago, he said...
我们会好好料理洛杉矶街上的那些拿枪的混混们
We will hold court against gunmen in the streets of Los Angeles.
我要把他们赶尽杀绝
I want them brought in dead, not alive,
对于任何姑息养奸和对罪犯表示同情的下属 我将做出严厉的斥责
and I will reprimand any officer who shows the least mercy to a criminal.
他挑选了警队里最暴力的50个人
He picked 50 of the most violent cops on the force,
给他们发了中型枪械 以及朝任何反抗人员射击的许可
gave them machine guns and permission to shoot anyone who got in their way.
他把他们叫做炮团
He called them the Gun Squad.
不需要律师，没有诉讼，没有问讯，不处分，不调查
No lawyers, no trials, no questions, no suspensions, no investigations.
只剩下一摞摞尸体
Just piles of bodies.
停尸房、医院甚至路边，到处都是尸体
Bodies in the morgues, bodies in the hospitals, bodies by the side of the road.
洛杉矶警局不是想要消灭犯罪，根本不是
And not because the LAPD wanted to wipe out crime. No.
洛杉矶警局是想要消灭竞争
The LAPD wanted to wipe out the competition.
克瑞尔市长和炮团里一半的人都有入股
Mayor Cryer and half the force are on the take.
赌博、卖淫、走私酒，只要你报的出来
Gambling, prostitution, bootlegging, you name it.
如上帝在伊甸园里所做的那样
Because once you give people the freedom to do whatever they want,
只要给予人们做任何事的自由 他们会毫不犹豫地去做我说的那些事
as the Lord found in the Garden of Eden, they will do exactly that.
警察局决不容忍有反抗和异议的存在
This police department does not tolerate dissent, or contradiction,
甚至是让他们难堪的情况
or even embarrassment.
而你，你让他们脸上很不好看 这让他们很不高兴
And you are in a position to embarrass them and they do not like it.
他们会利用一切的手段来诋毁你
They will do anything in their power to discredit you.
我不知道见过多少次了，现在已经开始麻木了
I've seen that happen too many times to start going blind now.
所以我才想要见见你
That's why I wanted to meet you,
我要告诉你，你让自己陷入了怎样的境地
to let you know what you're getting yourself into
而且我希望能帮助你抗争到底 如果你是这样决定的话
and to help you fight it, if you choose to.
牧师先生，很感谢你为我做的一切
Reverend, I appreciate everything that you're doing
还有你所告诉我的信息
and everything that you said,
但是我没有这样的想法
but I'm not on a mission.
我只想找我的儿子回家
I just want my son home.
柯林斯太太，有不知多少母亲的孩子
Mrs. Collins, a lot of mothers' sons
已经因为这一点便宜私利而成为了牺牲品
have been sacrificed to expediency around here.
你的孩子，很遗憾，肯定不是第一个
Your son, unfortunately, would not be the first.
但如果你能做出正确的选择，也许他将是最后一个
But if you do it right, he may very well be the last.
他只有两条路来选
He had two cavities that needed filling.
由他来引出这次战斗，而我负责处理
He put up a fight, but I took care of it.
还有呢
And?
你儿子的门牙之间有条缝，也就是齿隙
Your son's upper front teeth were separated by a small tissue, a diastema.
两颗牙齿之间大约有1/8英寸的距离
It made them sit about an eighth of an inch apart.
房间里那孩子的嘴里却没有
The boy in that room has no such gap.
牙齿也会随年龄改变么？他们是这么宣称的
Can that change with age? Because that's what they're gonna say.
在某些情况下，的确是有可能的
In some cases, yes, it's possible.
但是沃特牙齿之间的那条缝是不可能长拢的
But the tissue between Walter's teeth prevents that from happening.
不通过手术是无法办到的
See, they can never come together without an operation to sever the tissue,
而且我现在就可以明确地告诉你说 他从来没有接受过这样的手术
and I can tell you right now that he has never had such an operation.
你能不能将这些话写到证词里？
Would you be willing to put that officially in writing?
请原谅我的粗鲁，我绝对帮你
Pardon my language, but hell yes.
看来麻药的效果过去了
Sounds like the anesthetic's wearing off.
或者，我应该先去写证词
On the other hand, maybe I'll write that letter first.
给这个小家伙一点时间好好想想
Give the little fella something to think about.
如果真是那样的话，他的变化也太大了点
Well, if it is, he's changed enormously.
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
你是个老师
You're a teacher.
没错，但是老师也有名字啊？ 我的名字叫什么？
Yes, but even teachers have names. What's mine?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
我认识你，但是我不记得你的名字了
I know you, but I don't remember your name.
是福克斯太太 好了，去你位置坐下吧
Mrs. Fox. Now, take your seat.
我说的不是让你坐下，是让你回自己位子坐下 安排给你的那个位子
I didn't say take a seat. I said take your seat, the one assigned you.
你应该知道自己的位子在哪里 你可是坐了快一年了
You must know where it is, you've been sitting in it for over a year now.
柯林斯太太, 如果他是你的儿子 我就把教尺吃下去
Mrs. Collins, if that's your son, I'll eat my yardstick.
我不仅会帮你提供证明，我还愿意到法庭上给你作证
Not only will I put it in writing, I will testify to it in a court of law
如果需要的话，我可以给卡尔文・柯立兹总统写信
or to the President Calvin Coolidge himself if I have to.
谢谢你
Thank you.
今天晚上的广播见
I'll see you tonight for the broadcast.
祝你好运
Good luck.
就几个问题，女士
Quick question, ma'am.
就几个问题
Quick question!
柯林斯太太
Mrs. Collins.
你好，我的名字是克莉斯汀・柯林斯.
Hello. My name is Christine Collins.
早上好 早上好
Good morning. Good morning.
在3月10号，我9岁大的儿子沃特・柯林斯失踪了
On March 10th, my nine-year-old son, Walter Collins, disappeared.
经过5个月的调查
And a five-month investigation
他们从伊利诺斯州的德卡博带回来一个男孩
led to a boy being brought to Los Angeles from DeKalb, Illinois.
他们告诉我，也告诉大家说这个孩子就是我的儿子
They told me and all of you that this boy was my son.
他其实不是我的儿子
He was not my son.
洛杉矶警局弄错了
The LAPD made a mistake,
因为这个孩子的变化太大了
and that is the reason for the supposed transformation.
我这里有他的医生和老师提供的证明
I have letters from his teachers and his doctors
都能够证明他不是我的儿子
all confirming that he is not my son.
我已经拿去复印了，明天我就拿给你看
I'm having them reprinted now, and I'll have them for you tomorrow.
我给了洛杉矶警局好多次机会来纠正他们的错误
I have given the LAPD every opportunity to admit their mistake
还有重新开始搜索我的儿子
and renew the search for my son.
但他们一直拒绝那样做
Since they have refused to do so,
所以我不得不把事情公之于众
it has forced me to bring my case public.
我希望这样做能说服他们 把这个问题给圆满处理好
And I hope that this now will persuade them to finish what they started
然后把我真正的儿子送回家
and bring my son home to me.
谢谢大家
Thank you very much.
莫雷利！
Morelli!
我要你去找那个叫柯林斯的女人，带到这里来
I want you to find the Collins woman and get her here.
还有，比尔，带她从后门进来
And, Bill, bring her in the back way.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
这边，女士
This way, miss.
为什么我们要从后面绕？
Why are we going in the back?
这是上尉的命令，前面都是记者
Captain's orders. Front's jammed with reporters.
太太，请坐，琼斯上尉马上就过来
Please, sit down, miss. Captain Jones'll be right with you.
嘿，有人要接手加拿大的案子么， 伊巴拉你空着么？
Hey! Anyone want to take a call from the Canadian Mounties? Ybarra?
他们怎么了？丢了头麋鹿？
What'd they do, lose a moose?
他们要抓一个从加拿大偷渡过来的小鬼
They need a juvenile living here illegally deported back to Canada.
他和他的表哥一起住在怀恩威尔河边的一座农场里
He's living with his cousin on some ranch near Riverside, in Wineville.
你来接？ 我来接
You want it? I'll take it.
我空的实在没事做了
Got nothing better to do.
你简直就是个王子
You're a prince.
柯林斯太太
Mrs. Collins.
你可以让这男孩待在这儿，她会照顾好他的
You can leave the boy. She'll take care of him.
请坐
Sit.
你给我们造了不小的麻烦啊，柯林斯太太
Oh, you've caused us quite a bit of trouble, Mrs. Collins.
整个警察局都对这样的情况感到很失望
This situation has become an embarrassment for the entire police department.
我没有想要让任何人尴尬
It wasn't my intention to embarrass anyone.
哦，当然不是，你当然不想
Oh, no, of course not.
作为对我们的回报，你告诉报纸说我们连几个孩子都分不清？
You just told the papers we couldn't tell one boy from another as a compliment
为了你这个案子我们忙了好几个月
for the months we spent working on your case.
你是把我们都当白痴吗？是不是？你很开心吗？
You trying to make fools out of us? Is that it? You enjoy this?
我没有
Of course not.
我希望你们能找到我的儿子
I want you to find my son.
你知道你的问题在哪里吗？柯林斯太太？
You know what your problem is, Mrs. Collins?
你只是想逃避一个母亲应尽的责任
You're trying to shirk your responsibilities as a mother.
你说什么？
What?
你不想要个拖油瓶，对不对？
You enjoyed being a free woman, didn't you?
你只是不想要有孩子拖累吧
You enjoyed not having to worry about a young son.
那样你就可以去自己想去的地方 做自己想做的事情
You could go where you wanted, do whatever you wanted,
还有见任何你想见的人
see anyone you wanted.
结果我们找到了你的儿子，而且我们把他带了回来
But then we found your son, and we brought him back.
现在他又变成了你的负累
And now he's an inconvenience to you.
所以你才炮制了这个谎言
And that's why you cooked up this scheme,
好把这个孩子丢给州政府，让政府来帮你抚养他长大
to throw him to the state and get the state to raise him for you.
是不是这样？ 才不是这样！
Isn't that true? That is not true!
不是？就连那个孩子自己都说是你的儿子
No? Well, even the boy says he's your son.
他为什么会那么说？
Why would he say that?
他怎么会无缘无故那么说？
How would he know to do that?
我不知道，我只知道他在撒谎
I don't know. I just know he's lying.
哦，大概是吧，也许他在撒谎
Oh, maybe so. Maybe he is a liar.
他从小就是这么被教的吧，对不对？
But that's how he's been trained, isn't it?
你们两个都是天生的骗子
Lying was born in both of you.
要我说，你就是个骗子，只会给我们制造麻烦
You're a liar and a troublemaker and, if you ask me,
在洛杉矶街上巡逻的可不是你
you got no business walking the streets of Los Angeles.
现在给我听好了
Now wait a minute.
要不就是你明知自己在撒谎
Because either you know you're lying,
或者就是你神智不清，不知道自己是撒谎还是在说真话
or you're not capable of knowing if you're lying or telling the truth.
你到底是哪一种呢？
So, which is it?
你是个失职的母亲？还是脑子有毛病？
You a derelict mother? Or just plain nuts?
因为在我这里，你只有这两个选择
'Cause from where I sit, those are the only options.
我没那么多时间来听你的废话
I'm not gonna sit here and take this.
你要专家？还是要医生？我这里都有不少
You want experts? You want doctors? I have a few of my own.
玛顿
Matron.
柯林斯太太，你还要坚持说那边的男孩不是你儿子吗？
Mrs. Collins, you still insist that the boy out there is not your son?
是的，他不是我儿子
Yes, I do.
不要再嘴硬了 什么？
Please, don't struggle. What?
不要！ 你这样做只会伤害到自己
No! You'll only hurt yourself.
你要做什么？ 站好
What are you doing? Hold still.
你不能这么做，不行，你不能这样
You can't just do this. No, you can't.
你将会被移送到
You are to convey the prisoner
洛杉矶综合医院的精神病院去
to the Los Angeles County General Hospital Psychopathic Ward.
你说什么？
What?
下面是你入院的原因
You are to make the following entry.
被告声称他被警察和其他人蒙骗
Defendant states she's been deceived by police and others,
坚持说我们给了她一个并非她儿子的男孩
and that we have given her a boy and tried
并且强迫她承认这是她自己的孩子
to make her think it is her son when she says it is not.
- 把她带走 - 不，不，不
Take her away. No. No, no.
求你，求求你
Please. Please.
走吧，柯林斯太太
Come on, Mrs. Collins.
不，不
No. No.
这里
This way.
我们于1928年3月10日见到柯林斯太太
Mrs. Collins has been known to us since about March 10th, 1928
她向我们报告说她9岁大的儿子沃特失踪了
when she reported her nine-year-old son, Walter, missing.
男孩在1928年8月被发现
The boy was gone until August 1928. Okay.
在孩子回家之后，她继续声称自己的儿子仍然失踪
Since his return, she has complained that he is still missing
一再要求继续寻找他的儿子
and has made repeated requests that he be found.
鉴于她存在妄想，受迫性幻觉和现实认知错位等症状
She suffers from paranoia, delusions of persecution and dislocation from reality.
可能对自己和其他人造成一定的威胁
She may be a threat to herself or others.
我们建议将她移送至精神病院
We recommend that she be conveyed to the psychopathic ward
直到她恢复神智为止
until her senses can be restored.
又是12号
Got another code 12.
姓名？
Name?
柯林斯，克莉斯汀
Collins. Christine.
不，不，听我说，这是个错误
No, no, no, listen, this is a mistake.
签发人是？
Certifying officer?
林肯高地分局，J.J.琼斯上尉
Captain J.J. Jones, Lincoln Heights Division.
不，不要，求求你！求求你！ 那些警察是想惩罚我…
No, no, please! Please! The police are trying to punish me...
如果你再吵吵闹闹，我就给你穿紧身衣？
If you keep it up, I'm gonna have to put you in a straitjacket.
要穿吗？
Do you want that?
不，长官
No, ma'am.
那就给我老实点，12号
Then behave yourself. Code 12.
我没有发疯！
I'm not mad!
求求你
Please.
哦，上帝
Oh, God.
没事的
All right.
不！
No!
住手！
Stop!
分开你的双腿
Spread your legs.
干什么？
What?
分开点
Wider.
哦
Oh.
我没有病！
I'm not sick!
摸我！摸我！
Touch me! Touch me!
进去，这里就是你的房间
Inside. This is your room.
医生今天出去了，他明天早上会来看你
The doctor has left for the day. He will see you in the morning.
我可不…可不可以跟负责的人谈一下
Can I... I need to speak to somebody in authority.
抱歉
Sorry.
我的房间！，不，不 这是我的房间
My room! No. No, no, no, this is my room.
我能打个电话吗？
Can I make a phone call?
只有表现好才能打电话
Phone privileges are earned by good behavior.
根据规定，你不准看书、看报纸、杂志和听广播 也不允许拥有尖利物品
You're not allowed newspapers, magazines, radio, books or sharp objects.
这是为了你的安全着想 请帮帮我！
This is for your own good. Help me!
听我说
Listen to me.
我的房间
My room.
不，这是我的房间
No, this is my room.
哦，上帝啊！
Oh, God!
我的房间
My room.
不，不，这是我的房间
No, no, this is my room.
我的房间
My room.
我的房间！我的房间！我的房间！
My room! My room! My room!
我的房间！
My room!
他们说这是我的房间！
They said it was my room!
有什么要帮忙的吗？
You have a problem?
引擎过热了，没什么大事 很快就会好的
Overheated, that's all. She'll be fine in a bit.
嘿，听我说，能不能帮我个忙？
Hey, listen, could you give me a hand?
我要找一个叫做诺斯考特农庄的地方 就在怀恩威尔
I'm trying to find a place called the Northcott Ranch, up by Wineville.
诺斯考特农庄吗？
Northcott Ranch, huh?
哦，对，没错
Oh, yeah, yeah.
你就要到了
You're almost there.
你只要…你只要沿着这条路往西走
You just... You just follow this road west,
大概还有两，不，还有三英里
about two, no, three miles.
之后你往右开
And then you take that next right.
沿着路一直往前开就到了
And you stay on that and it will bring you right to it.
那边出什么事情了？
Is something going on out there?
没有
No.
就是有个少年犯的案子
Just looking into a juvenile matter.
谢谢你的帮助
Thanks for your help.
不用谢
Sure.
有人吗？
Hello?
嘿！
Hey!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
过来！过来！
Come here! Come here!
我们是警察！
This is the police!
我要逮捕一个叫桑佛德・克拉克的小子
I have a warrant for a minor named Sanford Clark.
把门打开，靠墙站好
Open the door or stand aside.
嘿！站住！
Hey! Stop!
站住！给我站住！站住！
Stop! Stop it! Stop it!
别动！再动我就把你的脸摁到地板里去
Stop it! Stop it or I'll push your face through this floor!
别动！
Stop it!
好吧！
Fine!
把手伸出来
Give me your hands.
过来，坐下
Come on. Sit down.
上帝啊！
Jesus!
孩子，你到底怎么了？
What the hell is wrong with you, kid?
啊？
Huh?
你难道不知道袭击警察是违法的吗？
Don't you know assaulting a cop is against the law?
有什么区别吗？
What difference does it make?
我们会把你送回加拿大去，小子
We're just sending you back to Canada, son.
又不是什么世界末日
It isn't the end of the world.
什么？
What?
小子，美国可不是你想待多久就多久的
Well, you can't stay in the U.S. As long as you want, pal.
联系上柯林斯太太了吗？
No word from Mrs. Collins?
我们没有她的消息
We haven't heard from her.
去她的家看看她是不是出事了
Get on down to her house, make sure she's all right.
如果她不在屋子里的话，找她的邻居打听下
And if she's not there, check with her neighbors.
看看他们知道些什么
Find out what they know.
好
Absolutely.
现在有请圣保罗教会的
And now KGF welcomes the Reverend Gustav Briegleb
古斯塔夫・布里格勒博牧师
of St. Paul's Presbyterian.
我是圣保罗教会的古斯塔夫・布里格勒博牧师
This is Pastor Gustav A. Briegleb of St. Paul's Presbyterian Church,
在KGF电台为您主持主的世界
bringing you the Lord's word on Radio KGF.
晚上好
Good evening.
我今天晚上一直在等一位嘉宾
I had hoped to have a guest with us tonight,
不过显然她是迟到了
but apparently she has been delayed.
既然她不在场，没法复述下午她告诉媒体的话
And since she cannot be here to tell you what she told the press this afternoon,
就由我来讲述这个故事吧
I'll have to fill in as best I can.
由我来告诉大家发生了什么
I'm going to tell you what happened
每天晚上我都会在这里向大家播报新的情况
and I'm going to keep on telling you every night, right here,
直到有人出面做他们应该做的事为止
until somebody does something about it.
前往沙漠本地，45号列车
The Desert Local, train number 45,
5分钟后会在2号道口进站
will be arriving on track two in five minutes.
你好，我要买张去加拿大的票
Hello. I'd like a ticket to Canada.
阿尔伯塔或者温哥华 只要是今晚的票就行
Alberta or Vancouver, whatever's leaving tonight.
今天晚上没有那么远的车
I don't have anything going that far tonight.
最远的话我可以给你一张去西雅图的火车票
The best I can do is put you on a train to Seattle.
你可以在那里换乘，或者开车穿过国境
From there you can transfer to a local or drive across the border.
那也可以
That would be fine.
要回程票吗？
Roundtrip?
单程的
One way.
那就是15块
That'll be $15.
好
Right.
给你
There you go.
谢谢，这是你的票，旅途愉快
Thank you. There you go. Enjoy your trip.
当然
I will.
半个小时后吃早餐
Breakfast is half an hour.
求求你了，女士，我要见负责的医生
Please, miss, I need to see a doctor in charge.
餐厅就在楼下
The dining room is down the hall.
等医生准备好了自然会喊你的
The doctor will call for you when he's ready.
你要鸡蛋，还是麦片？
Do you want eggs or oatmeal?
好了，所有人都到齐了
Okay, that's everyone that's here.
那么
All right.
吃麦片吧
You can pull the oatmeal.
你明天也吃麦片吗？
Do you want it for tomorrow?
都丢掉，对，就这样
You know, just dump it. All right.
你应该吃东西
You should eat.
吃饭才显得你正常
Eating is normal.
你要处处显示出自己很正常才行
You gotta do everything you can to look normal.
这是你出去的唯一机会
It's the only chance you got.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
芭芭拉，你得吃东西 我不饿
Barbara, you have to eat now. I'm not hungry.
我叫我叫卡罗尔・德克斯特 你叫什么名字？
My name's Carol Dexter. What's yours?
克莉斯汀 克莉斯汀・柯林斯
Christine. Christine Collins.
把东西都吃光吧，我知道会很辛苦 但你得吃饭
Now, finish it all. I know it's hard, but you gotta try.
哦，天啊
Oh, boy.
我听见他们的谈话了
I heard them talking.
你也是因为12条进来的？
You're here on code 12?
警察干预
Police action.
我是说，这里的医生和工作人员都认为
I mean, the doctors, the staff, they figure
如果是警察带你进来的
that if the police brought you here,
那就是有道理的
there must be a good reason for it.
根本没有什么理由
There isn't a good reason for it.
我很正常，我会找时间向他们解释
I'm perfectly sane and I will explain that to them.
怎么解释？
How?
你表现得越正常，就越显得你有病
The more you try to act sane, the crazier you start to look.
如果你笑得太多，就是有幻觉，要不就是精神错乱
If you smile too much, you're delusional or you're stifling hysteria.
但如果你不笑呢，就是你抑郁了
And if you don't smile, you're depressed.
如果你一点表情都没有，那就是情感丧失 有可能发展成紧张性精神分裂
If you remain neutral, you're emotionally withdrawn, potentially catatonic.
你想的很多
You've given this a lot of thought.
没错，你还不明白吗？
Yeah, I have. Don't you get it?
你是12条，我也是
You're a code 12, so am I.
我们进来的原因是一样的
We're here for the exact same reasons.
我们都把条子给惹毛了
We both pissed off the cops.
你看看，你看到那边那个女人了吗？
Now, you see, you see that lady there?
她找个了老是揍她的警察老公
She was married to a cop who kept beating her up.
当她想把真相告诉别人的时候，他把她丢进了这里
When she tried to tell somebody about it, he brought her here.
我还要些果汁
I want more juice.
还有她
And that one?
把你的托盘放回原位
Put your tray back where it belongs.
然后当她想把事情透露给报纸的时候
The police beat the crap out of her brother, broke both his arms.
警察把他弟弟狠揍了一顿，打断了他的双手
When she tried to tell the papers...
你是怎么回事呢？
And you?
我做的夜班
I work nights.
嗯？
Sure.
我是说，我晚上出来找活
I mean, I work nights.
哦
Oh.
对，在城里的俱乐部里
Yeah. In the clubs. Downtown.
对不起
I'm sorry.
然后，有个客户一直打我，他一直打，不停手
Yeah, well, this one client just kept hitting me and he wouldn't stop,
然后我去投诉
so I filed a complaint.
结果却发现他是个条子
And it turns out he was a cop.
接下来我知道的就是我被送进了这儿
Next thing I know, I'm here.
可是他们没有权力这么做
But they can't do that.
你开玩笑吧？
Are you kidding?
All right, one more and then that's it.
大家都知道女人很脆弱
Everybody knows women are fragile.
我是说，女人都很情绪化，没有逻辑 上不来台面
I mean, they're all emotions, no logic, there's nothing going on upstairs.
来人哪，救救我
Somebody! Help me!
每过一段时间她们都会有一些不方便
Every once in a while they say something that's a little inconvenient,
那时候她们就会脑子不清楚
they just go fucking nuts.
我的法国口音重，不好意思
Pardon my French.
你可以吃完的，你就要吃完了
You gotta get those dishes. You got it.
如果我们都是疯子，那么就不用管我们说什么
If we're insane, nobody has to listen to us.
我是说，如果是你，你会相信谁？
I mean, who are you gonna believe,
是想要破坏警队团结的几个疯女人
some crazy woman trying to destroy the integrity of the force,
还是相信警察？
or a police officer?
他们把我们丢进这里的好处就是，既让我们闭上了嘴 又顺便教了我们怎么做人
Then once they get us in here, we either shut up and we learn to behave,
要不然我们就别想回家了
or we don't go home.
你都吃完了吗？
Are you all done?
或者，我们会像那样子回家
Or we go home like that.
住手，住手！
Stop. Stop it.
别拍！别拍
Stop it! Stop it.
求你了
Please.
克拉克
Clark.
桑佛德・克拉克
Sanford Clark?
这里
Here.
文件下来了
Paperwork's come through.
你会在后天被遣返回加拿大
You'll be deported back to Canada day after tomorrow.
加拿大警察会决定该怎么处置你的
Police there will decide what to do with you next.
我希望你在这段时间里好好反省过了
I hope your stay here has convinced you not to try crossing the border
以后不会再偷偷越境了
illegally in the future.
等等！
Wait!
我想跟带我进来的那位长官谈谈
I'd like to talk to the officer who brought me in.
我想他这会儿有更重要的事情要做
I'm sure he has far more important things...
求你了，是很重要的事情
Please. It's important.
克莉斯汀・柯林斯.
Christine Collins.
谢谢 柯林斯太太
Thank you. Mrs. Collins.
我是乔纳森・斯蒂尔医生 请坐
Dr. Jonathan Steele. Please, have a seat.
我希望你在这里过得还算不错
I hope your stay with us has been comfortable so far.
嗯
Yes.
真的？
Really?
我以为第一次进来都会比较难受
I'd think it'd be quite difficult at first.
的确如此
Yes, it was.
当然不好受，不过我觉得还多了
Of course it was very difficult, but comfortable enough.
我看到他们做了… 他们抽了血做测试
I see that they have... They've taken a blood test.
瓦色尔曼氏测试
The Wassermman Test.
他们说是为了检查有没有梅毒 梅毒会影响大脑
They said it was to check for syphilis, 'cause it affects the mind.
听到别人觉得你应该去检查梅毒
The idea that someone thinks you need to be checked for syphilis,
你会不会觉得很沮丧
does that upset you?
不会，他们说只是依照惯例，我不觉得有问题
No, they said it was standard procedure, so it did not.
对，当然，标准流程
Yes, exactly. Standard procedure.
我们必须做到面面俱到
We have to cover all our bases.
我可以理解
I can imagine
也许对有些人来说会不好受
that for some people that would be uncomfortable,
我可以理解
but I understood.
根据你的记录，你怀疑警察
According to your file you believe that the police substituted
用假的男孩来冒充你的儿子
a fake boy for your son.
我不是说的真假
No, I didn't say he was a fake boy.
他不是我的孩子
He's not my boy.
他们找错孩子了
They brought home the wrong boy.
我的儿子依然不见踪影
My son is still missing.
是吗？那就奇怪了，因为我在这张报纸上
Well, that's strange, because I have here a newspaper article
看到了一张你在火车站迎接儿子回家的照片
with a photo of you at the train station, welcoming home your son.
这照片上的人是你没错吧？
That is you in the photo, isn't it?
是我
Yes.
确定？
Yeah.
是我
Yes.
也就是说，一开始他是你的儿子
So, at first he was your son,
然后现在他又不是你儿子了
and now he's not your son.
这样的情况存在多长时间了？
Has this been going on for a long time?
人会长大，变成其他的样子？
People changing, becoming something other than what they are?
人不会变
People don't change.
你觉得人不会改变？
You don't think people change?
不是，我不是…
No, that's not...
他们逼迫过你吗？
The police, they're not out to persecute you?
没有，他们没有
No, they're not.
警察是来保护你的
The police are here to protect you.
是的
Yes.
你确定？
Really?
是的
Yes.
这就更奇怪了，因为你一开始被送进来的时候
Well, that's odd because when you were admitted,
告诉我们的护士长说 警察想要给你一个惩罚
you told the head nurse that the police were conspiring deliberately to punish you.
是护士长和实习生都有份惩罚你？
So, either the head nurse and the interns are also conspiring to punish you
还是你的故事内容又变了
or you're changing your story.
你是不是经常会分不清现实和幻想，柯林斯太太？
Do you often have trouble telling reality from fantasy, Mrs. Collins?
没有
No.
抱歉这种天气里还把你叫出来，警探先生
I'm sorry to bring you out in this weather, Detective,
但是这孩子一直很抗拒
but the boy has been quite insistent.
那也很正常
It's all right.
我先来听听他想要说什么 然后回家把自己弄干
I'll see what he has to say so I can go home and get dry.
这种下雨天 外面到处都是阿猫阿狗和民主党人
It's raining cats, dogs, and Democrats out there,
所以最好别让我白跑一趟
so this had better be worth it.
又是你？
You again, huh?
让我们看看
We'll see.
好了
Well?
很不容易，对吧？
This isn't easy, okay?
什么意思？
Yeah?
大老远地冒着暴雨开车过来也不是件容易事
Driving my ass here in the pouring rain wasn't easy either.
高顿・诺斯考特是我的表弟
My cousin is Gordon Northcott.
你找到我的那个农庄是他的
He owns the ranch where you found me.
他说我可以在他离开的时候替他照顾这儿
He said I could live there in exchange I watch the place when he's gone,
打打杂，干干家务之类的
doing chores and stuff like that.
还说我可以想待多久就待多久
Said I could stay as long as I wanted to.
于是我就以为我也可以随时离开
I thought that meant I could leave whenever I wanted.
~
Mmm.
你的意思是说他把你当囚犯一样关了起来？
You saying that he held you prisoner?
胡扯
Bull.
我去的时候可是看到你自由的像只松鸦一样
When I got there, you were running around free as a jaybird.
只要你愿意，随时都可以离开嘛
Could've left any time you wanted.
不是的
No.
那又是什么？
So, what's this, huh?
随便编造一个故事 好解释你为什么会非法入境？
Some kind of story to cover why you're in the country illegally?
不，不是那样的
No, it's nothing like that.
我也没兴趣听你讲故事，你懂么？
'Cause I don't have time for this, okay?
听我说！他说…
Listen to me! He said...
说什么？
What?
他说了什么？
What did he say?
他说如果我敢走人的话，他就把我干掉
He said that if I tried to leave, he'd kill me.
听着，你不明白他是怎样一个人
Look, you don't understand what he's like,
还有…他做了什么，他逼我做了什么
what he... What we did, what he made me do.
好吧
All right.
那我们从头说起
Let's start at the beginning then.
他逼你做了什么？
What'd he make you do?
我们杀了一些小孩
We killed some kids.
你说什么？
What?
你听我说，我不想干的，我发誓 是他逼我帮他杀人
Look, I didn't mean to, I swear. He made me help him.
他说如果我不动手的话，他会连我也一起杀掉
He said if I didn't, he'd kill me, too.
你得帮帮我，求求你了，我很害怕
Look, you gotta help me, please. I'm so scared.
我不想因为杀小孩下地狱
I don't want to go to hell for killing kids.
你看
Look.
什么孩子，你到底…你到底在讲什么？
What kids? What... What are you talking about?
我不知道，我根本不知道他们的名字
I don't know. I never knew their names.
名字？
Names?
多少个？
How many?
多少孩子？
How many kids?
一共加起来？
All together?
大概有20个吧，我想
About 20, I guess.
不，你在撒谎
No, you're lying.
我没有，我发誓都是真的
No! It's true, I swear!
你难道要告诉我说你杀了20个小孩？
You're gonna tell me you killed 20 kids?
嗯！大概那么多
Yeah! Thereabouts.
我后来就没有数了
I stopped counting after a while.
高顿说大概有1、2个逃跑了
Gordon said maybe one or two may have escaped.
但是…
But...
不可能
No.
不可能有人杀了20个孩子好吗
Nobody can just up and kill 20 kids, okay?
我们真的做了
We did.
是我们杀的
怎么杀的？
How?
大多数时候我们就杀一两个
Most times we'd just have one or two.
有时候会是三个
Sometimes as many as three.
我们准备离开农场的时候我就得
I always knew when we were getting ready to leave.
把车擦干净
Clean up the car.
确认轮胎都有气
Make sure the tires were good.
检查引擎
Check the engine.
因为他担心车子会抛锚
'Cause he was afraid that the car would break down
然后我们会被逮住
and we'd get caught.
我可怜的孩子
My loving baby
每一次我们都会挑不一样的方向走
We'd always go a different direction every time.
从来不在镇子的同一个地方停留两次
Never hit the same part of town twice.
很多次我们就这么一直开啊开
Sometimes we'd just drive around for hours,
直到我们发现了孩子
till we found somebody.
你在这里！
Well, there you are!
我们找你都快找疯了？
We've been looking for you like mad.
你是谁？
You have?
当然
Sure thing.
听着，你的小伙伴出事了
Listen, your folks, they've been in an accident.
他们伤的很严重，派我们来找你
And they sent us to come find you. Now, they're hurt real bad.
警察已经把他们送去医院了，所以没有空来找你
The police took them to the hospital, but they didn't have time to come find you,
我跟他们说我可以去找你
so we said that we would do it.
快点，马上走
Now, come on.
好了，快点进来
All right. Get in here. Hurry.
听着，我们会带你去医院，带你去看你的伙伴
Listen, we gotta get you to that hospital so you can see your folks.
你瞧，一般小孩子不会和一个陌生人上车
See, a lot of kids won't get in a car alone with a stranger,
但如果还有一个小孩在
but when he's got a kid there...
还有一个小孩
There's a good boy.
让开点，让开点，桑
Scoot over. Scoot over, San.
事情就好办多了
...that made it easier.
你抓紧了
I want you to hold on tight.
他们会看着我，然后想
They'd look at me and say...
我们要走很长的路
We've got a long way to go.
“如果他没有事的话”
"Hey, if he's safe... "
我们会开得很快
And we are gonna fly.
“我也不会有事的”
"... I guess I will be, too. "
每次看着他们爬进卡车里
Every time they got in the truck,
我只想死
I just wanted to die.
等我们回到农场以后，就把他们关进仓库里
As soon as we got back to the ranch, they went in the coop.
你们饿不饿？
You boys hungry?
啊？
Huh?
看好门，桑佛德！
Watch the door, Sanford!
嘿！看着门！
Hey! Watch the door!
怎么了？
What's the matter?
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
你是不是担心我会伤害你？
Are you worried that I'm gonna hurt you?
我不会弄伤你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
来，过来
Huh? Come here.
不要，不要 过来，我不会伤害你的
No! No! No! No! Please! I would never hurt you.
有些时候他会立即杀人
Some days he'd do them right off.
有时候他会等几天
Other days he'd wait,
再去多抓几个
pick up a few more,
等到有4、5个的时候才动手
until he had about four or five of them.
对
Yeah.
不要，不要，不要！ 不要什么？
No! No! No! No what?
不要什么？啊？
No what, huh?
过来！过来！过来！
Come on. Come on. Come on!
桑佛德，给我盯好门外！
Sanford, keep your eye on that door!
不要，求求你，不要！不要！
No! Please, no! No! No!
不，不要！不要过来！ 求求你，不要！不要！
No! No! No! No! Please! No! No!
有时候，他…他会留下
He'd... He'd sometimes leave
一两个人，勉强还有口气
just one or two of them alive, barely, anyway.
然后他会跟我说
He'd say,
把他们干掉…桑
"Finish them, San.
“你去把他们干掉，或者…或者让我把你干掉”
"Finish them or... Finish them or I'll finish you. "
于是我照做了
And I did.
我杀了他们
And I killed them.
是我干的
And I did.
我杀死了他们
I killed them.
上帝啊，我杀死了他们！
Oh, God, I killed them!
哦，上帝啊！
Oh, God! Oh!
嘿
Hey.
什么？
What?
看着我
Look at me.
这些孩子
These kids.
如果再让你看到他们的样子，你能不能认出来？
You think if you saw them again, you think you might be able to recognize them?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能吧
Maybe.
嘿，我有好些时间没有更新过这个了
Hey, I haven't updated these in a while, but still.
我只要…
Just...
大概，只要看下这些就行了，可以么？
It should be. Just go through these, okay?
如果发现你认得出的，直接把照片拿出来 摆到这边的桌上
If you see any you recognize, just put them down on the table here.
对不起！
I'm sorry!
哦，我的上帝
Oh, my God.
我不想的…是他逼我的
I didn't mean to... He made me.
哦，他妈的
Oh, shit.
这一个，看着我
This one. Look at me.
你确定么？
You're sure?
确定
I'm sure.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
哦，我的天哪！我的天哪！
Oh, God! Oh, God!
上帝！
Jesus Christ.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
哦，我的老天
Oh, God.
好吧，他是在撒谎
Well, he's lying.
你脑子抽风了么？莱斯？
Have you gone soft in the head, Les?
整整二十个孩子，长官
Twenty kids, sir.
他在耍你呢
He's playing you.
他知道自己肯定麻烦了 所以搞出这种狗屁故事来糊弄人
He knows he's in trouble, so he's come up with some cock and bull story
说什么自己是被迫留在这里的
about how he was forced to stay in the country.
那是你的看法，长官 我不这么认为，你没有看见他的表情
With all due respect, sir, I don't think so. You didn't see him.
这小子已经被吓得半死，浑浑噩噩了
This kid, he's scared half out of his mind.
他还挑了那个叫柯林斯的小鬼 我们已经找到那孩子了，你还记得不？
He picked the Collins kid. We found him, remember?
你没读报纸吗？
Haven't you been reading the papers?
可能你已经读过了 我说的对吗？
Or maybe you have, is that it?
长官，请你听我说
Sir, if you'd just listen to me...
上尉，对不起，他又来了
I'm sorry, Captain, but he's here again.
- 谁？ - 那个布里格勒博牧师
Who? That Reverend Briegleb.
他在打听克莉斯汀・柯林斯的事
He's asking about Christine Collins.
好吧，那你去告诉那个煞笔
Well, you tell that son of a bitch
让他快点从警察局里他妈的滚出去
to get the hell off of police property,
不然我就以扰乱治安罪逮捕他
or I'll have him arrested for disturbing the peace.
我说了，但是他说他不会离开 他还带了人来
I tried. He said he won't leave, him or his friends.
什么？
What?
哦，真他妈的该死！
Oh, what the hell!
上帝！
Jesus!
哦，上帝都去死吧
Oh, Jesus jumped down.
上尉？
Captain?
- 伊巴拉 - 我在
Ybarra? Yeah.
听我说，你给我回来，什么都不要做
Listen to me. You're to do nothing except get back here.
长官，根据警局的规定
Sir, departmental policy requires that
所有谋杀案都要进行调查
all allegations of homicide have to be investigated.
看在上帝的份上，这些可是孩子啊
These are kids, for Christ sake.
我刚才的话就是局里的规定
Departmental policy is what I say it is.
现在我命令你带着那个孩子滚回来，听到没有？
Now, I'm ordering you to get your ass back here with that kid, you got that?
你谁都不要讲，然后给我把那个孩子带过来，听明白没？
You don't talk to anybody and you bring me that kid. You got it?
不准告诉任何人！
Nobody!
- 琼斯上尉 - 伙计们
Captain Jones. Boys.
你把克莉斯汀・柯林斯怎么了？
What the hell have you done with Christine Collins?
不要给我装腔作势说些虚的
And don't try and lie your way out of it,
有好几个邻居都看见她坐上一辆警车走的
because several of her neighbors saw her being driven away in a police car.
柯林斯太太因为精神崩溃
Mrs. Collins has been placed in protective custody
现在正在我们的保护性监管中
following a mental breakdown.
精神崩溃？
A what?
她正在接受最好的治疗
She's getting the best treatment available.
事情就是这样
And that will be all.
下一个
Next.
过来 接受什么？
Go on. Move up. For what?
药物治疗
Medication.
为什么要做药物治疗？ 对你有益
Medication for what? The kind that's good for you.
能够帮助你休息
Help you relax.
但是我不想要休息 别这样
Well, I don't want to relax. Come on.
我什么药都不需要… 那我们将强制你服用
I'm not gonna take something... We can force-feed you
如果你希望我们用这样的方式的话 我不知道这是什么药！
if that's what you want. I don't know what it is!
我不知道，斯蒂尔医生 抓住她
I don't know what it is. Dr. Steele? Take it. Orderly.
斯蒂尔医生？
Dr. Steele?
我明白，过来吃药
I understand. Come on.
女士，继续走，过来
Ladies, keep moving. Come on.
我不知道这是什么东西，我不要吃
I don't wanna take anything that I don't know what it is.
我什么病都没有，我不用接受药物治疗
There's nothing wrong with me that I need medication.
你的确没有什么问题
There's nothing wrong with you.
你没有问题 没有
No, there's nothing wrong. No.
你很健康？ 是的，我很好
You're fine. Yes, I am.
那么你应该能够在这个上面签字
Well, then you shouldn't have any trouble signing this.
签了这份东西，你要承认
By signing it, you certify that you were wrong
警察还给你的孩子不是你儿子这话是错的
when you stated the boy returned to you by the police was not your son.
这上面还声明警察把你送到这里
It further stipulates that the police were right
接受看护是有必要的 他们不必对此承担任何责任
in sending you here for observation and it absolves them
签字吧
of all responsibility. Sign it.
我不会签字的
I won't sign that.
我不会在上面签字的
好吧，那说明你的情况没有好转
Well, then your condition is not improved.
签完字，明天一早你就可以出去
Sign it, and you can be out of here first thing tomorrow morning.
可我根本没错
But I wasn't wrong.
他不是我儿子，我的儿子还失踪着
He's not my son. My son is still missing.
柯林斯太太，你开始激动了
Mrs. Collins, you're becoming agitated.
是的，我是很激动…我不签 因为他不是我儿子！
Yes, I'm, yes... I'm not signing that, because he's not my son!
看护员！
Orderly!
他不是我儿子！ 看护员！
He's not my son! Orderly!
我的儿子还没有找到
My son is missing!
这个病人精神错乱了 我没有！我的儿子失踪了！
The patient is becoming hysterical! No! My son is missing!
去看看镇静剂是不是有效
See to it she is sedated properly.
- 把她带出去 - 不！不！不！
Get her out of here. No! No! No!
下一个！ 不！
Next! No!
不！不！ 看护员，抓住她
No, no! Orderly, hold on.
住手！
Stop it!
该死！张嘴！ 张开，张嘴
No! Open your mouth. Open, open your mouth.
冷静！ 你抓好她了？
Easy! You got her?
上帝啊！ 吞下去
God! Swallow it.
住手！
Stop it!
退回去
Move back.
你！ 把她带走！
You! Get her out of here!
过来，你找到她了？
Come on, you got her?
不准插手，这跟你们没关系 这是警察在办事！
Stay out of this! This is none of your business! This is police business!
你们所有人都别动！都不准过来 如果你们还有点脑子的话！
All of you! You'll stay out of it if you know what's good for you!
你不知道你已经惹上很多麻烦了么
You'd think you were in enough trouble with the law already,
臭婊子，你不明白么？
being a whore, wouldn't you?
攻击管理人员 把她关进18号房间去
Attacking a staff member. Room 18.
不，不要！住手！不要！
No, no! Stop it! No!
不！不！
No! No!
不！住手！
No! Stop it!
过来，孩子
Come on, kid.
我不知道，我也不能确定 我想应该是的，他长得很像
I don't know. I'm not sure. I think so. He was pretty close.
等下
Excuse me.
- 没事的，接下来我来吧 - 但是我
It's all right, I can take it from here. But I got...
我们有话要问他
We need him for questioning.
我来就好了
Like I said, it was dark.
谢谢 过来
Thanks. Come on.
布拉迪，罗斯
Brady, Ross.
你们两个被正式征用了，跟我走 路上我再给你们解释
You've just been requisitioned for backup. I'll explain on the way.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
我也不确定，她说她小时候得过哮吼 也可能是肺炎
I'm not sure. She said she'd had the croup before. This could be pneumonia.
我一直在劝她，但是她不答应
I keep telling her that, and she doesn't want to.
你必须坚持
You have to insist.
你不应该那么做
You shouldn't have done that.
求求你，让我出院！ 进去！
Please, let me out! Get in there!
我自找的
Wanted to.
感觉很好
Felt good.
让我出去！不要！求求你！不要！ 你找到她了？
Let me out! No! Please! No! You got her?
我在赤脚医生那里堕了两次胎
I lost two babies to back alley doctors.
我没有选择
No choice.
我根本连为自己的孩子斗争的机会都没有
Never had the chance to fight for them.
而你有
You do.
不要放弃
Don't stop.
我不会的
I won't.
都他妈的去死，让他们马上风死
Fuck them and the horse they rode in on.
这可不是一个有教养的女人说的话
That's not exactly language for a lady.
去死吧
Hell.
有些时候就该说这样的狠话
There are times that's exactly the right language to use.
什么时候？
Yeah?
当你已经一无所有的时候
When you've got nothing left to lose.
你不应该待在这里
You're not supposed to be here!
嗯嗯
Mmm. Mmm.
待着这里，检查房子，还有仓库
Stay there. Check the house. Check the barn.
没有人
It's all clear.
这里也安全
Clear here.
拿铲子给我
Bring me that shovel.
好了，我们走吧
All right. Let's go.
过来
Come on.
你指给我看
You're gonna show me.
指给我看
Come on. Show me.
这里？
This it?
你确定？
You sure?
嗯
Yeah.
挖开
Dig.
既然你说你把他们埋起来了，那么这里就应该有尸体
You put them in the ground, you can take them out of the ground.
挖吧
Go on. Dig.
听到我说的没有，挖
You heard me. Dig.
我的天哪
My God.
哦，天啊
Oh, my God.
叫他进来
Call it in.
去叫验尸官来 把方圆20英里内所有的警察叫来
Get the coroner and every officer
让他们1个小时内到
in a 20-mile radius here inside the hour.
给我发信息通缉高顿・斯图尔特・诺斯考特
Then put out an APB on Gordon Stewart Northcott.
所有的资料都在我车里，继续挖
The information's in my car. Go on.
不用再挖了，小子
You can stop, son.
停下吧，够了
You can stop now. It's over.
嘿
Hey.
我们会接手负责的，接下来交给我们 我们会…
We'll take it, we can take it from here. We can take it from...
接下来我们会管的， 听到没有？够了
We can take it from here, okay? It's over.
没事了
It's okay.
没事的，没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
都结束了
It's all over.
没事了？
Okay?
文件
File.
大家回避
Privacy, please.
我知道你一直拒绝药物治疗，所以我们将强制服用
I see that you've been refusing medication, requiring force feeding.
好了，麦克 吃午饭了？
All right, Michael. Lunchtime?
柯林斯太太，已经6天了 一点效果都没有
Six days, Mrs. Collins, and no progress.
我们可能有必要采用一些更激进的疗法了
We may have to move on to more strenuous therapies.
除非你愿意向我们证明说你的病情开始好转了
Unless you're willing to prove that you're doing better
只要你签掉这个
by signing this.
去死吧，让你马上风死吧
Fuck you and the horse you rode in on.
关她去18号房间
Room 18.
我现在就要见负责人
I want to talk to somebody in charge, right now!
你是谁？
Please.
这里谁负责的？
Who is in charge here?
打开
Open.
我是这里当值的主治医师
I'm the head doctor on duty.
你就是把克莉斯汀・柯林斯关起来的那个医生？
You're the doctor who locked up Christine Collins?
哦，对不起，先生
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
对于家属之外的人员，我们不便透露病情
We don't discuss cases with anyone other than family.
是吗，你这该死的家伙能解释这个么 自己看
Oh, you'll damn well discuss this one. Read it.
先生
Sir.
给我好好看
Read it.
住手
Stop.
柯林斯太太，我最后问你一次
Mrs. Collins, one last time.
你到底愿不愿意签这份声明？
Are you or are you not prepared to sign that letter?
我不签
No.
你可以离开了
You're free to leave.
什么？
What?
你的衣服在旁边的房间里，你可以在那里换衣服
Your clothes are in the next room. You can change there.
旁边的房间？
In the next room?
对，没错
Yes. That's right.
你自己去拿吧
See to it.
上帝
Christ.
漫长地不敢想象
Long as it's not the original.
不是的
No, it's not.
给你
Here it is.
那是谁的东西？贝克的文件？还是拉尔森的？
And who is that? Is that Baker's file or Larson?
贝克的
That's Baker.
他说他会…
He said he wanted...
护士，给我所有
Nurse, I wanna see
关于克莉斯汀・柯林斯太太的文件
every piece of paper you have on the case of Mrs. Christine Collins,
我现在就要，你听明白没有？
and I want to see it right now, do you understand me?
所有的文件，她什么时候能出来？
Every piece. When will she be coming out?
马上就能出来了
Oh, it's just up ahead.
哦，很好，我们…
Oh, all right. Let's...
暴风袭击了西棕榈沙滩
Hurricane hits West Palm Beach!
贝比鲁斯击出第53记本垒打
Babe Ruth hits 53rd home run!
河岸幼童谋杀案
Kids found murdered in Riverside! There it is.
洛杉矶史上最残酷的犯罪!
Biggest crime in Los Angeles history!
柯林斯的孩子可能已经死了！
Collins boy assumed dead!
请看这里！请看这里！
Read it here! Read it here!
柯林斯太太 我很遗憾
Mrs. Collins, I'm so sorry.
上尉，你处理克莉斯汀・柯林斯一案的方式
Captain, your handling of the Christine Collins case
让警局在公众面前闹了大笑话
has exposed this department to public ridicule.
这里不仅是民事责任了，还有刑法责任
There is even the possibility of civil and criminal liability.
长官，没有人会预先知道那个农场里发生了什么
Sir, nobody could've known what was happening up at that ranch.
我们不知道，治安官部门不知道 执法办公室也不会知道
Not us, the sheriff's department, or the marshal's office.
至于这个叫做柯林斯的女人
And as for the Collins woman,
我还是不太相信她的儿子也是怀恩威尔案的受害者之一
I'm still not convinced that her boy is among the victims up in Wineville.
你不相信？
No?
不相信
No.
这里还有4张失踪孩子的照片，长得都很像他
There were four other photos of missing boys that looked a lot like him.
那个克拉克可能认错了
The Clark kid could've been mistaken.
可能吧
Maybe he was.
但更重要的是，没人在乎他是不是认错了
Which begs the obvious question. Who cares?
长官？
Sir?
市长希望让这件事尽快被大家遗忘
The mayor wants this to go away.
我也这样希望
I want this to go away.
你所要做的就是默认沃特・柯林斯
The way you do that is to stop insisting that Walter Collins
也是在那间该死的庄园被杀的孩子之一
is not among those boys killed up at that goddamn ranch.
因为如果你带回来的那个孩子不是沃特・柯林斯
Because if the boy you brought back is not Walter Collins,
而他又没有死在农庄里，那他妈的这孩子到底会在哪里？
and he's not dead up at that ranch, then where the hell is he?
人们会开始想，为什么我们没有找到那小子
People are gonna want to know why we haven't found him.
为什么我们连尽职尽责都做不到
Why we're not doing our job.
相对的，如果
But if, on the other hand,
他是，或者可能是死在怀恩威尔的可怜孩子之一
he is, or could be, among those poor boys killed up in Wineville,
那么质疑的声音就不会出现
then the inquiries stop.
只是短暂的不愉快罢了
It's a momentary embarrassment
你得自己担起来
you're just gonna have to live with.
忍过这段糟糕的时间
Better a short inconvenience
总比一直拖着问题好 你说呢，上尉？
than a lingering problem, wouldn't you say, Captain?
是，长官
Yes, sir.
那个孩子已经失踪快1年了
The boy's been gone nearly a year.
就算能找到他，现在也不是时候
If he was going to be found, it would've happened by now.
不管他是不是在那个农庄里
Whether he was up at that ranch or not,
真相就是他可能死在别的地方了
the truth is he probably is dead somewhere.
最好他的母亲能马上知道这个消息，你说呢？
Better his mother accept that now than later, don't you think?
- 是，长官 - 很好
Yes, sir. Good.
就这样，上尉
That'll be all, Captain.
我们就照您所要求的去做 这事情就这样处理了
That's how you want it, then I guess we're done here.
跟地区监狱说，把他关押候审
Tell county jail we're remanding him for trial.
等等，我什么都没有做 事情发生的时候我根本不在场
Wait. I didn't do anything. I wasn't even here when it happened.
假装自己是沃特・柯林斯
By pretending to be Walter Collins,
你的所作所为干扰了警察对一宗 绑架谋杀案的调查
you're interfering in a police investigation of a kidnapping and murder.
如果找到证据，我们可以认定你是杀人犯的同伙
We can try you as accomplice to that murder after the fact.
太可惜了
That's too bad.
地方监狱可比少管所和孤儿之家要惨多了
County jail is a lot worse than a juvenile hall or a foster home.
糟糕得多
It's a lot worse.
你不能那么做 我还没有成年
You can't do that. I'm just a kid.
桑佛德・克拉克也是个孩子
Sanford Clark's a kid, too.
15岁，他会进监狱
Fifteen. He's going to jail.
谋杀犯和他的同伙都要进监狱，这个道理大家都懂
All murderers and their accomplices go to jail. Everybody knows that.
把他带出去，事情解决了
Get him out of here. It's out of my hands now.
等等，我不想进监狱
Wait. I don't want to go to jail.
那就证明你无罪
Prove it.
我…
I...
我知道汤姆・米克斯是在洛杉矶拍的电影
I knew Los Angeles is where they make the Tom Mix movies.
我就想，如果我能碰到汤姆・米克斯
I figured if I could meet Tom Mix
也许他会答应让我骑他的马
maybe he would let me ride on his horse.
他的马叫做托尼，你知道不？
His horse is named Tony. Did you know that?
你觉得怎么样了？
How are you feeling?
还好
All right.
还有一辆警察的车停在外面
The police still have a car outside.
我猜他们是想知道你接下去要做什么？
I guess they're waiting to see what your next move is going to be.
- 我要回家 - 然后呢？
I'm going home. And then?
然后，我能想到很多事情
Then, I've been giving it a lot of thought.
他们是怎么对待这些女人的 还有他们是怎么对待沃特的
And what they did to those women, and what they did about Walter.
我一直教他，永远不要主动动手，但要保证自己赢
I used to always tell him, "You never start a fight, but you always finish it. "
这次的事情不是我挑起来的，但是要由我来结束
And I didn't start this fight, but I'm gonna finish it.
柯林斯太太，你现在是个公众关注人物了
Mrs. Collins, right now you're a sufficiently high profile that I think
我想，现在警察就算想派人跟着你，也要考虑一下了
even the police would hesitate to go after you out in the open,
但是我必须警告你，事情的变化很快
but I have to warn you that could change very quickly
如果他们觉得自己的位置受到了威胁
if they feel their position threatened.
整个风向都会变，真的
Very quickly indeed.
他们现在想怎么对付我？
What are they gonna do to me now?
他们没有证据
They got nothing.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
加拿大，温哥华 1928年9月20日
嗨，姐姐
Hi, sis.
高顿
Gordon.
我都不知道你回来了
I didn't know you were back in town.
嗯，我几天前就回来了
Yeah, I got in a couple of days ago,
我想给你个惊喜，没有…没有什么问题吧？
figured I'd surprise you. Is that... Is that okay?
当然，当然没有 进来吧
Yes. Yes, of course. Of course, come on in.
我那个小侄女呢？
Where's that little niece of mine?
她进城里去了
She went into town.
晚上应该能回来
Should be back this evening.
呃，鲍勃在
Uh, Bob's here.
哦，那好
Oh, good.
呃，我是想问你，我能不能在你这里待段时间
Uh, I was gonna ask if I could stay on a couple days.
你要住下？
Staying?
对
Yeah.
我可不可以用下你的浴室
Listen, can I use your bathroom?
我开了很久的车，想要好好洗个澡
It's been a long ride and I could really use a shower.
- 当然可以 - 好
Of course. Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
他不是…
Is that...
没事的，去隔壁 我会给警察打电话的，快去
All right, go next door. I'll call the police. Hurry.
你好，需要我接什么号码吗？
Operator. How may I connect you?
长官，他就在楼上
He's upstairs, sir.
从另一边绕过去！截住他！
Go around the other side! Cut him off!
跟我来！ 是，长官
Come with me! Yes, sir.
我们行动！
Let's go!
柯林斯太太，我想请你见下我的朋友，哈恩先生
Mrs. Collins, I'd like you to meet my friend, Mr. Hahn.
柯林斯太太，对于你的遭遇我表示深深的遗憾
Mrs. Collins, my deepest condolences on your loss.
我们能进来吗？
May we come in?
谢谢你的关心
I appreciate the sentiment,
但是他们说…
but they've yet to find...
已经确认了我儿子的尸体
To identify the remains as my son.
恐怕没有那么容易放下吧
I'm afraid it never gets any easier.
5年前我的女儿因为小儿麻痹症去世了
I lost a daughter to polio five years ago.
我每一天，无时无刻不在思念她
There's not a day goes by when I don't think,
总是想，我应该把这个告诉克劳蒂
"I should mention this to Claudine. "
然后我才记起来，她已经不在了
Then I remember she's not here.
请坐
Please, sit.
我今天早上都在
I've been on the phone all morning
和警察总署的秘书交涉
with the appointment secretary of the police commission.
他们不同意让我出庭作证
They said that they won't let me testify
或者传召证人 说没有这个必要
at the hearing or call witnesses. That it won't be necessary.
我知道，我听到消息说检查总署
I know. My sources say the police commission
决定宣布说琼斯和洛杉矶警局没有错误
is going to say that Jones and the LAPD did absolutely nothing wrong,
他们要把责任都推到那个孩子身上
and that the real blame lies with the kid and with you
还有你给他们的工作带来了困扰 为了你的个人安全，他们不得不把你隔离
for being difficult and forcing them to put you away for your own safety.
那样的话我想我需要雇个律师 提起民事诉讼
Then I guess I would have to hire a lawyer, file a civil suit.
我找了城里最好的检察官
I went to the best attorney in town,
他和市里面打了4场官司，都赢了
a man who's sued this city four times and won.
可惜的是我们请不起他
Unfortunately, we can't afford to really hire him.
我明白
I see.
所以我会接受这个案子
Which is why I'm doing this pro bono.
很荣幸能够为你辩护，柯林斯太太
It would be my honor to defend your honor, Mrs. Collins.
在我做律师的15年里
In my 15 years as a lawyer,
从没有见过任何人像你这样坚持又倔强地争斗
I have never seen anyone fight as long or as hard as you have,
毫无疑问，正义站在你这一边
in what is so clearly in the cause of justice.
谢谢
Thank you.
让我看看，书架上有什么
Let me see what's on the shelf.
我来
I'll look.
你好？我可不可以…
Yes? May I...
我叫S.S.哈恩
My name is S.S. Hahn,
我手上有法庭的执行令 要求你们释放所有因为第12条行政令
and I have a court order for the immediate release of all women being detained
而被关押进这家机构的所有女性
in this institution under the designation code 12
并就将他们关押的理由的正当性提出质疑
pending a formal inquiry into the reasons for their detainment.
对不起，主管医生现在不在
I'm sorry, the doctor in charge is not here
大概要等到早上 女士，我清楚地和你说吧
until the morning. Madam, let me be clearer.
要不你就乖乖地照执行令说的给我名单
Either you will produce the people named in that court order,
要不然你会发现自己出现在铁栏杆后 而且是没有钥匙孔的那边
or you will find yourself behind bars, and I mean without a key.
我没有权限给你… 女士，请让一让
I can't authorize you... Madam, stand aside.
我能见她了？
Can I see her now?
当然，没问题 她怎么样了？
Sure. Absolutely. How does she look?
好了，朋友们，都退后 给他让条路
All right, fellas, step back. Let's give him room.
他在这里
Here he is.
诺斯考特先生 关于被捕，请你说几句
Mr. Northcott, any comment on your arrest?
诺斯考特先生 你现在是怎么想的？
Mr. Northcott, how are you feeling?
哦，我觉得挺不错的
Oh, I'm feeling fine.
正如你们所知道的，我度了个小假
I've been on a little vacation, as some of you know.
是个非常愉快的假期
It was a really pleasant vacation.
最近警察和我找了不少乐子
The police have certainly provided me with a lot of amusement.
你躲了多久？
How long you been in hiding?
你是怎么逃过警察追捕的？
How did you avoid capture?
别吵，别吵，都问够了
Easy, easy. That's far enough.
是吗，我可没有，对吧？
Well, I didn't, did I?
再来一张！
One more shot!
你见到报纸上自己的照片了吗？
Have you seen your picture in the paper?
我直到最近才知道有人要抓我
Didn't know anybody wanted me until just recently.
我没有逃
Didn't even try.
伙计，我的行李上还有我的名字缩写呢
My luggage still has my initials on it, fellas.
你知道警察为什么要抓你吗？
Did you know why the police were after you?
不知道，不过如果能不沾染上官司 我觉得会更好
No, but I figured it'd be a good idea if I were to just stay out of it.
你感到羞愧吗？先生
Any remorse, sir?
你有什么话要对被你谋杀的孩子的父母说吗？
Do you have anything to say to the parents of the children you murdered?
无可奉告
No comment.
再拍一张 看这里！
One more shot, this way!
克雷尔市长，事情太出人意料了
Mayor Cryer. This is unexpected.
的确
So was this.
传票，要求宣誓证词, 接受问讯.
Subpoenas, requests for depositions, interrogatories.
来自哈恩先生和他的新客户克莉斯汀・柯林斯
All courtesy of Mr. Hahn and his new client, Christine Collins.
局长，你不用凑那么近去看
You don't have to look them over too closely, Chief.
你那份传票很快就会送到的
Your own copies should be coming any time now.
本市议会也同意调查本案了
The city council has also agreed to look into this,
马上
starting immediately.
该死的！
God damn it!
我还以为事情总算过去了
I thought this was supposed to go away.
今年是选举年
This is an election year.
我可不想闹出这么大的负面新闻来
I can't afford this kind of press.
很快就会解决的，我已经告诉琼斯上尉怎么做了
It is going away, sir. I've instructed Captain Jones to deal with it.
我担心的是，就算他低声下气
I'm afraid, falling on his sword
道歉说他犯了错，也没法弥补了，局长
and saying he made a mistake isn't going to be good enough, Chief.
我们让他躲一阵子风头
If we take him out of the picture for a while,
直到庭审结束，等事情冷下来会比较好
just might help calm things down until the hearing's finished.
发生了什么事？ 你没有听说吗？
What is happening? Didn't you hear?
这是我见过的最庞大的抗议队伍了
It's the biggest protest I've ever seen.
抗议 对
Protest? Yeah.
都是支持柯林斯的 让人难以置信
Over the Collins broad, if you can believe that.
我们要公正！ 我们要公正！
We want justice! We want justice!
哦，天啊！
Oh, my!
哈里斯先生
Mr. Harris.
上帝的行事必然有他的道理，柯林斯太太
The Lord works in mysterious ways, Mrs. Collins.
真的吗？
Boy, does he ever.
女士们，先生们，请听我说
Ladies and gentlemen, can I have your attention, please?
这是有史以来参庭人数最多的一次
There are more people gathered in this chamber than have ever been in this room before.
所以我想请你们稍微克制一下你们的举动
Therefore, I ask you to refrain from demonstrations of any kind.
告诉我们真相！告诉我们真相！
Tell the truth! Tell the truth!
我们聚集在这里是因为我们都想知道事实的真相
We are all here because we want to know the real facts in this case.
我想一周之后，我们就能够知道事情的真相了
And everybody is going to be heard if we have to sit here for a week.
索普先生，我怎么没有看到警察总署的人？
Mr. Thorpe, I don't see any members of the police commission.
房间里有谁是警局的代表吗？
Are there any members of the police department in the room?
戴维斯局长在吗？
Is Chief Davis here?
琼斯上尉来了吗？
Is Captain Jones here?
这里有谁是代表警察的吗？
Is there anybody here representing the police?
柯林斯太太，请你和我一起到外面去下可以吗？
Mrs. Collins, could you come across the street with me for just a moment?
我想你应该看看这个
There's something I think you should see.
好吧，虽然我不希望在开庭前就要求中止
Well, I hate to call a recess before we've even started,
不过我想我得先打几个电话
but I think a few phone calls are in order.
警察方面希望审判能够在非公开的场合进行
The police decided it'd be best to keep this off the main docket
以免出现街对面那样的混乱局面
in order to avoid exactly the sort of chaos we have across the street.
柯林斯太太 我是莉安・克雷
Mrs. Collins. I'm Leanne Clay.
这是我的丈夫，约翰 你好
This is my husband, John. Hi.
我只是想表达我的同情
I just wanted to pass along my sympathies.
我们以为自己儿子戴维的消息已经够糟糕了
What we went through waiting to hear anything
结果现在
about our son David was bad enough, now this.
警察们对你的所作所为，实在是令人发指
But what the police did to you, there was no call for that.
太过分了
No call at all.
请起立
All rise.
请大家都坐下 法警
Please, be seated. Bailiff.
哦，嘿
Oh, hey.
我在报纸上看到你了
I saw you in the papers.
你真的很有胆量，敢跟这样的警察作对
You got a lot of moxie, standing up to the police like that.
请被告起立
The defendant will please rise.
高顿・斯图尔特・诺斯考特,
Gordon Stewart Northcott,
你被指控犯有3宗一级谋杀
you've been charged with three counts of murder in the first degree,
另有17项未确认指控正在接受地区检察官的调查
with an additional 17 counts under review by the district attorney's office.
你可认罪？
How do you plea?
我没有罪，法官大人
Oh, not guilty, Your Honor.
诺斯考特先生，请坐
You may sit, Mr. Northcott.
考虑到被告喜欢进行跨国旅行，所以不允许保释
In light of the defendant's penchant for international travel, no bail will be set.
法庭会在明天造成听取初步动议
This court will hear preliminary motions by tomorrow morning.
一名叫作沃特・柯林斯的男孩
The boy, Walter Collins,
在1928年3月10日失踪
was reported as missing, March 10, 1928.
之后我们进行了全国性的搜索
We then instituted a nationwide search.
在8月18日，我们接到一个电话
On August 18th, we received a cable indicating that a boy
告知在伊利诺斯州，德卡博发现了一名 符合他外貌特征的男孩
matching his description was found in DeKalb, Illinois.
经过问讯，他承认自己是沃特・柯林斯
Upon questioning, he admitted to being Walter Collins.
我们安排这个孩子坐火车回到了加利福尼亚
We then made arrangements for him to be transported back to California.
之后柯林斯太太告诉你说那个男孩不是她的儿子
Where Mrs. Collins told you the boy was not her son.
是的，她拒绝承认
Yes. She denied his identity
而各项证据都证明这孩子是她的儿子
in spite of all of the evidence pointing to the contrary.
但是后来的种种迹象表明
But, as subsequent events have demonstrated,
她说的是对的
she was correct.
那么，出于什么原因
So, what prompted you to send her
你要将她送去接受心理检查呢？
for psychological evaluation?
这个孩子是不是她的孩子
Whether or not this was in fact the correct boy
和我的决定没有关系
was not relevant to my decision.
在那段时间里，她的行为十分怪异
Throughout this period, she acted strangely.
她表现的很冷酷，淡漠，面无表情
She was often cool and aloof and unemotional,
特别是面对我们在德卡博找到的男孩时
especially when confronted with the boy we found in DeKalb
以及在我们后续的交谈中
and in our subsequent conversation.
她的种种奇怪表现
It was because of her
所以我同意将她送去洛杉矶综合医院
disturbing behavior that I submitted her for observation
在精神病院接受看护
to the psychopathic ward of Los Angeles County General Hospital.
就这么一下
Just like that.
你只不过打了个响指
You snap your fingers and an innocent woman
就把一个无辜的女人丢进了精神病院！
is thrown into the psycho ward!
- 不是被强制的 - 如果任何一个警察上尉
She wasn't thrown. Every family in this state is in grave danger
都可以用职权 在5分钟内将一个刚进入他办公室的女人
when a police captain can take a woman into his office
强制送进精神病院的话
and five minutes later
恐怕这个州的每一个家庭正受到这潜在的威胁
have her thrown into the psychopathic ward on his own authority!
她不算是被强迫的
She wasn't thrown.
我们没有强迫她！ 她不算是被强迫进去的！
She wasn't thrown! She wasn't thrown!
那是怎么样的呢？队长？
What was that, Captain?
我们没有强制遣送她 她是被护送入院的
She wasn't thrown. She was escorted.
护送，强制，用什么样的动词都没有区别，上尉
Escorted, thrown, the verb doesn't matter, Captain.
问题在于她是在没有逮捕令的情况下被关押的
What does matter is that her incarceration was ordered without a warrant.
我这里有一份洛杉矶州就克莉斯汀・柯林斯一案
I am holding a carbon copy
下发的精神错乱鉴定证词
of the affidavit of insanity that was issued in the case
的文件副本
of the State of California v. Christine Collins.
这份证词是谁签的字？
Who signed the affidavit?
是我
I did.
好吧，那么让我看下这个说法对不对
Well, now, let me see if I have this correct,
你们在没有逮捕令的情况下将一个女人关进精神病院里
a woman was thrown into the psychopathic ward without a warrant,
因为根本没有所谓的逮捕令存在
because no warrant existed.
等到逮捕令写好已经是几天之后了
And when it was finally written several days later,
那时候她人已经被关进病院里去了
there was no need to sign it or to go to a judge
也就不需要再签发或者向法官提交了
because she was already in the asylum!
是这样吧，上尉先生？
Is this correct, Captain?
理论上来说，是的
Technically, yes.
有时候非常规手段是必须的，因为我们是在处理…
Extraordinary steps were necessary because we were dealing...
我们是在处理非常的事件
We were dealing with an extraordinary situation.
我们被一个自称是沃特・柯林斯的小鬼给骗了
Now, is it our fault that we were being deceived
这是我们的错吗？不是的
by a boy who claimed to be Walter Collins? No.
光听孩子的话，再看她的奇怪表现
In light of his claims and her disturbing behavior,
谁会想到她说的是真的？
who wouldn't begin to think that there was something the matter with her?
因为她质疑了你？
Because she questioned you?
不是，是因为她不肯听我们说的！
No, because she wouldn't listen!
是因为她表现地很顽固！
Because she insisted on being obstinate!
因为她不愿意相信我们这样的职业警察
Because she tried to take matters into her own hand,
而是固执地想把所有事情掌控起来
best left to qualified officers!
而且，一旦涉及到公民不服从权…
Because once civil disobedience starts...
因为她在争夺自己儿子的生命！
Because she was fighting for the life of her son!
一个可能还活着的孩子
A boy who may have still been alive
而你却在浪费宝贵的时间，拒绝承认自己做错了
while you were wasting valuable time denying you had done anything wrong!
再之后
And in the end
你的处理方法就是把她送进精神病院，对不对？
that's what happened, isn't it?
而同时，在这一切发生的同时
At some point, while all this was going on,
沃特・柯林斯和其他的19个孩子一样
Walter Collins was brutally murdered,
在怀恩威尔的诺斯考特农庄里
along with as many as 19 other boys
被残忍的杀害了
at the Northcott Ranch in Wineville.
是不是这样，上尉？
Is that correct, Captain?
是的
Yes, it is.
这就是所谓的公正么？
It's a travesty.
我没有问题了
No further questions.
14号列车已经进站，请旅客们上车
Train number 14, now boarding on track...
那么，通过一番努力，我们终于能够确认
So, after much effort, we were able to identify this boy,
这个之前给我们惹来不少麻烦的孩子的身份了
who's been responsible for so much trouble lately,
他是爱荷华州锡达拉皮兹的亚瑟・赫金斯
as Arthur Hutchins of Cedar Rapids, Iowa.
此外，我们已经将涉嫌谋杀
Between this, and the arrest of the man suspected of murdering
真正的沃特・柯林斯的嫌犯逮捕了
the real Walter Collins,
我们解开了洛杉矶史上最大的两个谜团
we've cleared up two of the biggest mysteries in the history of Los Angeles.
我希望媒体的各位先生们
I hope you gentlemen of the press will give
能够不吝版面帮我们的功绩做些宣传
as much space to the good things we do
不要过分关注某些罕见情况造成的小失误
as the mistakes that are made on rare occasions.
先生们，请允许我们向各位介绍
Gentlemen, allow me to introduce you
孩子真正的母亲简奈特・赫金斯太太
to the boy's real mother, Mrs. Janet Hutchins.
亚瑟
Arthur.
但愿他没有给你们添太多麻烦
I hope he wasn't too much trouble for you.
哦，没有，一点也没有
Oh, no, not at all.
伙计，来张合照？
How about a photograph, fellas?
再来张
One more.
赫金斯太太
Mrs. Hutchins,
这是柯林斯太太，亚瑟一直和她呆在一起 她希望你能收下这些东西
Mrs. Collins, the woman he was staying with, wanted him to have these.
这是她给他穿的衣服
They're the clothes she let him wear.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
亚瑟，她真是个好人对吧？
Isn't that nice, Arthur?
向好心的长官说声谢谢
Tell the nice officer, "Thank you. "
我不要这些东西，给别人吧
I don't want them. Give them to somebody else.
这孩子真老成，不是吗？
Precocious little fellow, isn't he?
这不是我的错，都是警察的错
It's not my fault. It's the police.
他们说我是沃特・柯林斯的，不是我要说的 不是我的主意！
They said I was Walter Collins, not me! It wasn't my idea!
不是我的主意！ 上…
Not my idea! Get...
是啊，去怪警察吧
Yeah. Go blame the police for your own mistakes.
我们已经见多不怪了，不是吗？
We've seen a lot of that lately, haven't we?
照顾好自己，亚瑟！ 路上小心
Take care now, Arthur! Safe travels.
好了，伙计们 今天就到此结束了
All right, fellas, that's it for today.
先生，先生！那个孩子是什么意思？
Sir, sir! What did the boy mean by that?
3月10号那天，我下班回家
It was March 10th, and I came home from work,
发现我九岁的孩子沃特不见了
and my nine-year-old son, Walter, was gone.
琼斯上尉一直认定他知道的信息才是对的
Captain Jones was acting on information he believed to be correct.
沃特・柯林斯的牙齿间有裂缝 又叫做齿隙
Walter Collins had a diastema, also known as a diastema.
那个孩子从来没有进过我的教室
That child was never in my classroom.
我可以百分之百确定
I can certainly attest to that.
我们希望警察局的好心人们
We rely on our good friends in the police department
能告诉我们，是谁做出了
to point to us those people who exhibit behavior
这种社会不容的决定
which is socially unacceptable.
他比沃特上次量的身高矮了差不多4英寸
About four inches shorter than the last mark of Walter.
这些照片能够证明
Well, some of these pictures show
桑佛德・克拉克之前告诉我的
what Sanford Clark told me,
他的确参与杀害了这些孩子
that he did in fact help in the murder of these children.
谢谢你，警探先生
Thank you, Detective.
陪审团的众位
Gentlemen of the jury,
我想请你们好好看下这些照片
I ask you to take a good look at these images.
它们能够说明这些十恶不赦的罪行
They establish beyond any reasonable doubt
的的确确发生在我们眼前
the circumstances and the nature of these heinous crimes.
我在这儿，牧师先生
I'm in here, Reverend.
沃特还没失踪的时候 我经常在他睡觉的时候
When Walter was here, I used to walk by his room
到他的房间来
when he was sleeping.
就算现在我再也看不到他，也听不到他的声音
And even though I couldn't see him or hear him,
我还是能感觉到他的存在
I could feel him.
所以我觉得沃特还没有死
That's why I don't think Walter's dead.
我还能感觉到他
I can still feel him.
柯林斯太太... 别说了
Mrs. Collins... No.
我知道警察说了什么
I know what the police said.
但是那个地方，还有那些尸体
But that place and the remains,
他们没法进行鉴定
they couldn't be properly identified.
也许那个孩子弄错了，他不小心选了沃特的照片
And maybe that kid made a mistake when he picked Walter's picture.
我知道你不愿意接受事实
I understand you don't want to accept this.
没有哪个母亲能够承受
What mother would?
但是我觉得你是时候放开心怀
But I think it's time for you to move on
为了你自己活下去
and start over for yourself.
你的孩子也会希望你能好好活下去的
Your son would want you to move on.
也许
Maybe.
也许他希望我能够继续去找他
Maybe he'd want me to keep looking for him.
也许他还在什么地方等着我
Maybe he's somewhere waiting for me.
女士，我相信他一直在等我
I believe he is waiting, ma'am.
他一定还在那个地方等着
He's waiting in that place where
总有一天我们会和心爱的人团聚在一起的
we'll all go someday to be reunited with our loved ones.
到那一天，他会知道从头至尾
And on that day, he'll know from front to back, end to end,
你为他全心全意做过的所有事的 柯林斯太太
heart to soul, that you did everything you could, Mrs. Collins.
所有的一切
Everything.
我们得走了，女士
We should go, ma'am.
我等下就来
One minute.
现在宣布判决
This meeting will now come to order.
委员会已经听过了双方的证词
This committee has now heard all of the testimony,
综合双方所述的事实
and, in light of the facts presented,
我们建议对琼斯上尉作出
we recommend that the suspension of Captain Jones
永久停职的处理
be made permanent.
肃清！肃清！
Order! Please. Please.
佛曼先生
Mr. Foreman,
陪审团是否做出了裁决？
has the jury reached a verdict?
是的，法官大人
We have, Your Honor.
请被告起立
Will the defendant please rise?
此外，法庭将考虑对现有法律和执法程序
Second, that steps be taken to investigate a change
做出相应修改
in the prevailing laws and procedures by which a citizen
以避免出现城市公民因主观认定的原因
of this city can be subjected to incarceration
被关押进当地的精神病医疗机构
in the county's mental facilities.
请陪审团阅读判决
You may read the verdict.
陪审团认为被告高顿・斯图尔特・诺斯考特
"We the jury find the defendant, Gordon Stewart Northcott,
有罪，一级谋杀罪名成立
"guilty on all counts of murder in the first degree. "
最后，考虑到警察局在公众诚信方面的丧失
Finally, restoration of public confidence in the police department
经过委员会的同意
can only be achieved
我们认为应免除
by the removal of its chief of police,
警察局长的所有职务
and this committee so recommends.
本次庭审结束
This hearing is concluded.
在判决执行前，被告是否有什么要说的？
Does the defendant wish to make a statement before judgment is passed?
我必须说清楚一件事
I want to make it real clear
在这里，我从来没有获得过公平的待遇
that I never once got a fair shake from you,
包括法官大人
Your Honor,
还有这法庭上的每一个人
or from this court.
也只有她有这个该死的荣幸
The only one in here worth a good goddamn is her.
因为只有她没有在面对媒体的时候对我恶言相向
'Cause she's the only one who never badmouthed me to the press.
她是唯一一个知道内情的人
She's the only one who understands
她知道警察在背地里的勾当
what it is to be framed by the police
捏造些你从没有做过的罪名 够了
for something you didn't do. All right, that's enough.
接下来我就等着被扔进洞里
And then to just be thrown in the hole,
或者在某个角落里烂死
to just rot and to fester and to be forgotten
从公众面前消失，然后被遗忘，我说的对吧？ 高顿！
and fade away, isn't that right? Gordon!
律师！ 是不是？
Counsel! Isn't it?
我没有杀你的孩子 柯林斯太太
I never killed your boy, Mrs. Collins.
律师，说够了！ 我决不会杀他的
Counsel, that's enough! I would never do that.
我绝对没有伤害沃特的
I would never hurt Walter.
律师，请你管好你的客户
Counsel, get control of your client
我一定会把他绑起来，塞好他的嘴
or I'll have him bound and gagged!
他是个天使
He's an angel.
闭嘴，高顿 放开我！
Come on, Gordon. Get off of me!
现在坐下
Now get down.
高顿・斯图尔特・诺斯考特,
Gordon Stewart Northcott,
本庭作出宣判
it is the judgment of this court
你将被送入圣昆丁监狱
that you be conveyed to San Quentin Prison,
在那里接受两年的单独监禁
where you'll be held in solitary confinement for a period of two years,
直至1930年10月2日
until October 2, 1930.
你将在那天接受绞刑
On that date, you will be hanged by the neck until dead.
愿主宽恕你的灵魂
May God have mercy on your soul.
1930年9月30日
我可以休息10分钟吗？
Is it all right if I have a 10-minute break?
当然可以
Of course.
你知道吗
You know,
你应该考虑要不要
one of these days you might actually consider taking
真的去休息上10分钟
one of these 10-minute breaks.
对你有好处的
It might be good for you.
到时候看吧
We'll see.
我是克莉斯汀・柯林斯.
This is Christine Collins.
我昨天通过电话的
I called yesterday.
请问你可不可以再查一下文件
I was wondering if you had a chance to look through the files
是不是有符合我儿子沃特・柯林斯特征的报告
and see if there was a match to my son, Walter Collins.
我知道了
I see.
如果你方便的话
Well, if it's all right with you,
我下个月会再打过来，非常感谢你
I'll call back in a month. Thank you very much.
柯林斯太太 我只想…
Mrs. Collins. I was just...
是的，我明白
Yes, I know.
事实上，这也是我想见你的原因
In fact, that's why I wanted to see you.
是关于沃特 我们…
It's about Walter. We had a...
我们接到了一份非常奇怪的电报
Well, we received a very strange telegram.
是谁发的？
From who?
高顿・诺斯考特
Gordon Northcott.
他想要见你
He's asked to see you.
为什么？
Why?
他说他知道你还在继续找你的儿子
He said he knows you're still looking for your son,
在他死之前…
and before he dies...
他说作证的时候他撒谎了 说他没有杀沃特
He says he lied when he testified that he didn't kill Walter.
克莉斯汀，他终于还是承认他杀了你的孩子
Christine, he's willing to finally admit that he did it.
他说，如果你可以去监狱探望他一下的话
He says if you come up to see him in person,
他会当面把真相告诉你
then he'll tell you the truth, to your face
然后希望你能够安心
so that you can get on with your life
继续过自己的日子
and have some peace.
你知道的，他后天就要在圣昆丁监狱
As you know, he's set to be executed
被绞死了
the day after tomorrow at San Quentin,
所以你的时间不多了
so you don't have a lot of time.
我花了一整个早上来帮你准备所有的会面手续
It took me most of the morning to make all the arrangements.
我发现你是这30年来
Turns out, you're the first woman in 30 years
被州里允许和连环杀手见面的唯一一个女性
the state has allowed to visit a serial killer
而且是在处刑前晚
on the eve of his execution.
你一个人可以吗？太太？
You'll be all right, ma'am?
- 嗯 - 我们就在门口了
Yes. We're right at the door.
会面时间是20分钟
Twenty minutes.
你大概没有烟吧？
Don't suppose you got a cigarette?
诺斯考特先生，你让我过来探望你
Mr. Northcott, you asked me to come here.
你说，如果我过来看你的话
You said that if I did,
你会把关于我儿子的事情都告诉我
you would tell me the truth about my son.
对
Yeah.
没错，我是那么说的
You're right. I did say that.
但问题是
But see, the thing is,
我没有想到你真的会来
I didn't really think that you would come.
现在
And now.
现在… 现在怎么了？
And now... And now what?
我实在没有想到你会…
I just didn't expect that you'd...
我不想见到你
I don't wanna see you.
你不想见我？
You don't wanna see me?
不是，是，我说不了
No. See, I can't do this.
我不想和你说话，我现在实在没法和你说话
I don't wanna talk to you. I can't talk to you right now,
不是因为明天他们会把我绞死
not with what they're gonna be doing to me tomorrow.
那是另外一回事 柯林斯太太，给你发电报
It's one thing, Mrs. Collins, to send a telegram,
那很容易
that is really easy.
但等到你来了，现在看到你
But when it's here, right now, in person, you know,
我就是，我不行…
I just, I can't...
我现在说不出你想听的话，柯林斯太太
I can't tell you what you want to hear, Mrs. Collins.
为什么？
And why not?
因为我不想带着满嘴谎言死去
Because I don't want to go to hell with a lie on my lips.
你看，为了忏悔，我惩罚了自己
See, I did my penance,
我请求上帝宽恕我，而且我知道他原谅我了
and I asked God to forgive me and he did, so far as I know.
我之后一直表现的很好
And I have been really good ever since.
如果我现在说谎的话，如果现在我又犯戒的话
But if I lie now, if I commit any sins right now,
我就没有多少时间剩下了
I'm out of time here,
我绝对得不到第二次宽恕的
and I won't be forgiven again.
我要跟你说，我不要下地狱
And I'll tell you one thing, I am not going to hell.
我不想…
I'm not...
诺斯考特先生，是你叫我过来的
Mr. Northcott, you asked me to come here.
诺斯考特先生，请你看着我
Mr. Northcott, please look at me.
你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
是的，你明白，你明白的
Yes, you do. Yes, you do. Hmm.
你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son?
我说了，我现在不想跟你说话
I told you, I don't wanna talk to you right now.
你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son?
你有没有杀我的儿子？ 嗯
Did you kill my son? Hmm.
你有没有杀我的儿子？ 我不知道
Did you kill my son? I don't know.
你不知道？你不记得了？
You don't know? You don't remember?
你有没有杀我的儿子？ 哦，不知道
Did you kill my son? Oh, no.
回答我！你回答我！你回答我！
Answer me! You answer me! You answer me!
我都不知道他们的名字 你有没有杀我的儿子？有没有？
I don't know their names. Did you kill my son? Yes...
你最好不要理我
You better get off of me.
不然呢？ 哼嗯嗯
Or what? Hmm.
你有没有杀我的儿子？ 我不知道
Did you kill my son? I don't know.
你有没有…
Did you kill...
你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son?
你知道他的名字！ 我不知道，不知道
You know his name! Oh, I don't. No.
你知道他的名字！ 你说他是个天使！
You know his name! You called him an angel!
没有 你知道他的名字！
No. You know his name!
不，我不知道他的名字 你有没有杀我的儿子？
No, I don't know his name. Did you kill my son?
他们喊着自己爸爸妈妈的名字，希望他们来救自己 然后我…
They cried for their parents to come and get them and then I...
你有没有杀我的儿子？ 你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son? Did you kill my son?
回答我！ 不然呢？
Answer me! Or what?
回答我！
Answer me!
不然你要怎样？你想伤害我吗？
What are you gonna do? You gonna hurt me?
我想你下地狱
I hope you go to hell.
你有没有杀我的儿子？ 看守！嘿，看守！
Did you kill my son? Guard! Hey, guard!
你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son?
- 你有没有杀我的儿子？ - 太太，别这样
Did you kill my son? Ma'am, please.
- 别这样 - 你下地狱去吧！
Come on. I hope you go to hell!
我想你下地狱！我想你下地狱！
I hope you go to hell! I hope you go to hell!
对不起，女士
I'm sorry, ma'am.
你有没有杀我的儿子？
Did you kill my son?
高顿・斯图尔特・诺斯考特,
"Gordon Stewart Northcott,
你承认了自己所犯下的谋杀罪行
"you have been convicted of murder,
你被判处绞刑
"the penalty for which is death by hanging.
没有推迟和缓刑判决
"There have been no stays or reprieves,
因此，根据洛杉矶州的法律
"therefore the execution will go forward
处刑将立即执行
"as stipulated under the laws of the State of California. "
你有遗言要说吗？
Do you have any last words?
没有
No.
没有话说
Nothing.
忏悔过以后，我觉得自己被洁净了 牧师先生
I kept clean after I confessed, Reverend,
就像我之前说的那样
just like I said I would.
会不会…
Will it...
很痛？
Will it hurt?
求求你，不要太快
Please, please, not so fast.
不要让我走的那么快！
Please, don't make me walk so fast!
不要！求求你
Please, don't make me!
不要，我不想
No, I don't wanna.
不对！13步
No! Thirteen steps.
13步
Thirteen steps.
我根本没有碰他们，你们这些混蛋！
But I didn't touch them all, you bastards.
我根本没有碰他们 我根本没有碰他们
I didn't touch them all. I didn't touch them all.
求求你！
Please!
帮我祷告！
A prayer! Please!
上帝！
God!
求求你们，在这里的谁，帮帮我！
Please! Somebody here, please,
为我祷告！
say a prayer for me!
不，上帝，不要！
No, God. No!
不要！不要！
No! No!
平安夜
Silent night
圣善夜
Holy night
万暗中
All is calm
光华射
All is bright
照着圣母
Round yon Virgin
也照着圣婴
Mother and child
今晚我们会在我家里
We're having a party tonight
举行一个金像奖的派对
at my place for the Academy show.
你要来吗？ 不，我还有很多事情要做
You want to come? No, I have a million things to do.
哦，来吧，求你了
Oh, come on, please. Please!
手下的姑娘们把这里到巴尔的摩的电话线 给搞坏了
You girls blew the phone lines out from here to Baltimore.
得有人把电话线路修好
Someone's gotta fix them.
去吧，晚上好好玩，我听收音机就行了
Go, have a good night. I have the radio.
好的
Okay.
你确定？
You sure?
当然，我确定 好好玩去吧
I'm sure. I'm sure. Have a good night.
晚安 晚安
Good night. Good night.
听着，我真的…
Listen, I really...
你好，本
Hello, Ben.
我刚好要和穆索和佛兰克家的朋友一起吃饭
I'm meeting some friends at Musso and Frank's for dinner.
他们会排队准备入场参加电影典礼
They're gonna pipe in the movie ceremonies into the restaurant.
晚上一定很精彩
Should be quite a night.
如果你能来我会更开心
I'd love it if you'd come.
可惜我手上有很多工作要做
I just have so much work I should be doing.
晚安
Good night.
本？
Ben?
我…
I...
我压了2美金在一夜风流上
I put $2 down on It Happened One Night
赌它是最佳影片
to win Best Picture.
看来我是唯一一个觉得
Seems I am the only person that thinks
它能打败埃及艳后的人
it has a chance against Cleopatra.
不过，如果我们赢的话，你愿意在明天的晚餐上庆祝吗？
But, if it wins, do you wanna celebrate tomorrow night at dinner?
就这么说定了，克莉斯汀 再见
It's a deal, Christine. See you.
如果你的影片赢了，我会打电话给你
If your movie wins, I'll call you.
我会等着的
I'll be here.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
瘦子，埃及艳后
...The Thin Man, Cleopatra...
吹捧地过头了
Overrated.
还有一夜风流
...and It Happened One Night.
克拉克・盖博 克劳德特・科尔伯特
Clark Gable, Claudette Colbert.
我很确定
I rest my case.
请给我信封
May I have the envelope, please?
得奖的是一夜风流
And the winner is It Happened One Night.
我就知道！我就知道！ 我就知道！我就知道！
I knew it! I knew it, I knew it, I knew it!
晚饭我请！
Dinner is on me.
克莉斯汀・柯林斯？
Is this Christine Collins?
是我
Yes, it is.
我是克雷太太，你还记得我吗？
This is Mrs. Clay. Do you remember me?
克雷太太 我当然记得你
Mrs. Clay, of course I remember you.
我有些事情要找你
I just had to call you right off.
是什么事？ 警察刚刚给我打了电话
What is it? The police just called.
他们找到了一个男孩，克莉斯汀
They found a boy, Christine.
在哪儿？ 在林肯高地教堂附近
Where? Lincoln Heights Precinct.
我们现在正要过去
We're leaving right now.
我马上就过去
I'll be right down.
这里
Oh, here.
我现在就想过去看看他
I wanted to go to him right off,
但是他们说现在有很重要的事情要和他单独谈谈
but they said it was important to talk to him alone first.
他们确认了？ 他们很确定
Are they sure? They're sure.
不过更重要的是我很确定
But, more important, I'm sure.
是我的儿子
It's my boy, all right.
是戴维
It's David.
克莉斯汀，他还活着
He's alive, Christine.
他们在希思佩里亚找到他的
They found him up in Hesperia.
你从学校回家
You were walking home from school,
然后他们说让你帮忙找一只狗
and they told you they needed help finding a dog.
是的
Yeah.
那么，你上了卡车之后，发生了什么？
So, after you got in the truck, what happened next?
他们开车带我逛了好多时候
They drove me around for a long time,
最后我们在这个农场停了下来
then we ended up at this ranch.
过来 戴夫，过来
Come on. Come on, Davy.
- 戴夫！过来 - 放开我
Davy! Come on. Get off me.
别打架！ 别吵
Don't fight this much. Hey!
那里还有别的男孩吗？
Were there other boys there?
是的，我记得还有5个
Yeah. Five, I think.
不过，那是很久之前了
It was a long time ago, though.
嗨，孩子们 这是戴夫！
Hello, boys. This is Davy.
我知道你们会… 嘿！
I know you'll make him feel... Hey!
不，不，嘿！ 闭嘴！
No. No! Hey! Shut up!
你和他们说过话吗？
Did you speak to them?
说了？那你还记得他们的名字吗？
Yeah? You remember any of their names?
嗯
Yeah.
他们中有两个是兄弟
Two of them were brothers.
我想他们应该是姓文斯洛
I think their last name was Winslow.
大的那个应该叫杰佛瑞
The oldest one was Jeffrey.
还有个叫沃特.
And Walter.
沃特？
Walter?
你还记得沃特的姓吗？
Yeah. Do you remember Walter's last name?
柯林斯.
Collins.
沃特・柯林斯.
Walter Collins.
你只记得这些男孩的名字？还记得别的事吗？
Tell me something if you only remember some of the boys' names,
你怎么会记得他的全名的？
how come you remember his full name?
因为发生的事情？
Because of what happened.
沃特和杰佛瑞在说话
Walter and Jeffrey were talking.
- 拉起来 - 因为他们检查了周围
Pull it. They kept checking around
他们发现棚子旁边有块栅栏松了
and they found a part of the coop where the wire was all messed up.
当心！
Be careful!
快点！
Hurry!
也许我们能够挖个足够大的洞，然后逃出去
Maybe make enough room to get out of there and run.
我们跑出来以后就分开走
When we get out, we split up,
朝不同的方向跑，明白了吗？
go in different directions. Okay?
他们没法抓住我们所有人
They can't catch all of us.
肯定弄出了很多声响
It'd make an awful lot of noise.
轻点，明白吗？
Be quiet. You got it?
结果那个洞不够大，所以我们卡住了
And if it wasn't wide enough, then we'd be stuck.
等等，救命！帮帮我！ 快点，快点走
Wait. Help! Help! Come on, hurry!
我的脚卡住了，快点 救命，帮帮我！
My foot's stuck! Hurry, help! Help me, please!
他过来了！ 他…
He's coming! He's...
我的脚！
My foot!
他过来了
He's coming.
快点，快跑，跑！
Hurry, run, run, run!
嘿，你们这群小混蛋
Hey! What the hell are you boys...
哦！圣母玛丽亚！嘿！嘿！嘿！
Oh! Mary, Mother of God! Hey! Hey! Hey!
你们滚回来！ 嘿！站住！嘿！
You get back here! Hey! Hold it! Hey!
嘿！
Hey!
别跑！
Stop!
去抓其他的人
Check on the others!
站住！该死的！
Stop! Damn it!
臭小子们，我跟着你们了！
Boys, I'm coming after you!
该死！该死!
Damn it! Damn it!
小家伙们，不管你们跑到哪里，我都会找到你们的
Boys, I'll find you no matter where you are!
他们不在这里了 过来，上车！
They're not in there! Come on! Get in the car!
我会找到你们的！该死的！ 快点上车，他妈的！
I'm gonna find you! Damn it! Damn it! Come on.
妈的！上车！ 桑佛德！
Shit! Get in the car, Sanford!
那是我最后一次看到他们
That was the last I saw of any of them.
也就是说你也不知道另外两个人后来有没被抓住？
So, you don't know if either of the other two were captured?
不知道
No.
我知道的是
All I know is,
如果没有沃特回来找我
if Walter hadn't come back for me
我大概永远没有机会逃出来
I don't think I ever would've gotten out of there.
好吧
Okay.
之后发生了什么？
So, what happened after that?
我朝着大路一直跑
I kept off the main roads,
然后看到火车在岔道口听了下来 就跳了上去
until I saw a train stopped at a crossing and I jumped in.
你为什么不告诉别人发生了什么？
Why didn't you tell anyone what had happened?
我害怕
I was afraid.
我以为他们回来抓我
I thought they'd come after me, or my folks.
所以我谁都没有告诉
So, I just didn't tell anybody.
我一直是一个人待着 后来有位蓝欣小姐给我免费的饭吃
I was on my own until I got a free meal from this lady, Miss Lansing.
我告诉她说我是个孤儿，就一个人
Told her I was an orphan, on my own.
她说我可以留下
She said I could stay on.
于是我就待了下来
And I did.
每个晚上
Every night,
我都会惊醒，以为他们就在窗外等我
I'd wake up thinking they were right outside my window.
然后我在广播里听警察说了
And then I heard the police talking on the radio
在农场里发生的事情
about what happened at the ranch.
于是我想，现在我大概可以回家了
And I thought, "For sure I can't go back now. "
为什么？
Why?
为什么不回家？
Why not?
因为我没有告诉任何人发生过什么
Since I didn't tell anybody what happened.
我害怕他们会骂我 会为了那些孩子的死怪我
I was afraid they'd blame me for those kids being dead.
所以我一直躲在外面不敢回家
So I just stayed away.
那这么多年之后，你为什么现在回来了呢？
What made you come forward now, after all this time?
嗯？为什么现在找警察？
Hmm? Why come forward now?
我真的很想我妈妈
I really miss my mom.
我真的很想我爸爸
I really miss my dad.
我想回家
I just wanna go home.
我只想回家
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
我爱你
I love you.
我还是不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
案子已经结束5年了，大家都以为他死了 然后他又出现了
Five years, case closed, everyone thinks he's dead, and there he is.
如果没有沃特的话，他肯定回不来
Wouldn't be, if it wasn't for Walter.
柯林斯太太，你的儿子很勇敢
Your son did a brave thing, Mrs. Collins.
你应该为他骄傲
You should be very proud of him.
我为他骄傲
I am.
你觉得他还活着？
You still think he's out there?
为什么不？
Why not?
警探先生，那天晚上有三个孩子逃了出去
Three boys made a run for it that night, Detective.
如果一个人逃脱了
And if one got out,
那么其他两个人中至少会有一个能逃出来
then maybe either or both of the others did, too.
沃特可能也逃了出来，而且和这个孩子一样 他心里害怕
Maybe Walter's out there, having the same fears that he did.
不敢公开自己的身份，也不敢回家
Afraid to come home and identify himself,
或者是害怕自己会再惹上麻烦
or afraid he'll get into trouble.
不管是哪种情况
But either way,
今天晚上的事给了我一些以前没有的东西
it gives me something I didn't have before tonight.
是什么？
What's that?
希望
Hope.
庭审结束后,琼斯上尉被停职,戴维斯局长被撤职 克雷尔市长没有得到再次参加竞选的机会
布里格勒博牧师继续用他的电台节目 揭露警察的不端行为和政要的收贿受贿
为了消弭丑闻带来的影响 加利福尼亚的怀恩威尔更名为米拉罗马
克莉斯汀・柯林斯一直没有停止找寻她的儿子